<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xmlAnswer>

<!--
   <record>
       <attribute name="headline"></attribute>
       <attribute name="date"></attribute>
       <attribute name="tag"></attribute>
       <attribute name="category"></attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
-->

<record>
  <attribute name="headline">SchistoDB 26 Released</attribute>
  <attribute name="date">15 Oct 2015 13:00</attribute>
  <attribute name="tag">schistodb10_15_release</attribute>
  <attribute name="category">release</attribute>
  <attribute name="item">
    <![CDATA[
    <p><strong>We are pleased to announce the release of SchistoDB 26</strong></p>

    <section>
      <h3>New Features</h3>
      
      <section>
       <h4>GBrowse Track Search </h4>
        <ul>
          <li>
            The Select Tracks page in the Genome Browser now includes a search function.  Search for specific tracks 
            based on a word or phrase from the track title or category.   
            <a href="http://luffa.gacrc.uga.edu/swfeltz/images/GBrowse_news_item.jpg">image<a>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </section>
      
      <section>
       <h4>New Tutorials</h4>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <a href="https://youtu.be/qGLkAEzQpqU">Find genes with an enriched GO term<a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="https://youtu.be/0fkkJJ9f2cw">Downloading untranslated regions of genes<a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="https://youtu.be/dfx7CCr1_uo">Download sequence for genes in a search result<a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="https://youtu.be/ByBAYywzSWU">Downloading sequence from a gene page<a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="https://youtu.be/3DtOwQM9Cts">Download the sequence of all genes for an organism<a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="https://youtu.be/XNUgT6HEjGY">Download the Sequence (fasta) and Annotation (gff) files for a genome<a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="https://youtu.be/1-onu5raD6M">Downloading coding sequence<a>
          </li>
          <li>
            <a href="https://youtu.be/b2hgT65H4CQ">Downloading protein sequence<a>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </section>
      
      <aside>
        Note: Our bimonthly database releases incorporate new data and correct old data when necessary.
        Changes in annotation and new experimental data may slightly alter your search results by increasing or decreasing the number of hits.
        When search parameters change with a new release, we invalidate (Ø) the search and ask you to rerun it.
        When IDs are updated or removed, we map the old IDs to the new ones, remove the old IDs from your Basket, and leave your Favorites page alone.
      </aside>

    </section>
    ]]>
  </attribute>
</record>

<record>
  <attribute name="headline">SchistoDB 25 Released</attribute>
  <attribute name="date">23 July 2015 13:00</attribute>
  <attribute name="tag">schistodb7_15_release</attribute>
  <attribute name="category">release</attribute>
  <attribute name="item">
    <![CDATA[
    <p><strong>We are pleased to announce the release of SchistoDB 25</strong></p>

    <section>
      <h3>No new data or functionalities in this release</h3>

      <aside>
        Note: Our bimonthly database releases incorporate new data and correct old data when necessary.
        Changes in annotation and new experimental data may slightly alter your search results by increasing or decreasing the number of hits.
        When search parameters change with a new release, we invalidate (Ø) the search and ask you to rerun it.
        When IDs are updated or removed, we map the old IDs to the new ones, remove the old IDs from your Basket, and leave your Favorites page alone.
      </aside>

    </section>
    ]]>
  </attribute>
</record>

<record>
       <attribute name="headline">SchistoDB 24 Released</attribute>
       <attribute name="date">13 April 2015 13:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">schistodb4_15_release</attribute>
       <attribute name="category">release</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">
           
         <![CDATA[
We are pleased to announce the release of SchistoDB in collaboration with the EuPathDB resources.  This first release includes the genome sequence and annotation 
of <i>Schistosoma haematobium</i> Egypt and the assembled genome sequence of <i>Schistosoma japonicum</i> Anhui and <i>Schistosoma mansoni</i> Puerto Rico.  
Additional information about these genomes is available in the <a href="/a/getDataset.do?display=detail#Genomes%20and%20Annotation">dataset section</a> of SchistoDB.  
We look forward to working with you as we integrate additional genomes and functional data over the coming years.
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

 <record>

       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         Beta SchistoDB 3.0 is released with three species, Schistosoma mansoni, S. japonicum, S. haematobium
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">01 July 2012 00:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">01July2012Release3.0</attribute>
       <attribute name="category">release</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[

We are pleased to announce that the beta SchistoDB is now available at <a href="http://beta.schistodb.net/">beta.schistodb.net</a>.  SchistoDB is supported by ApiDB/EuPathDB (<a href="http://eupathdb.org">www.eupathdb.org</a>).
<br><br>
  Please send a message to the support team from the link at the bottom of the SchistoDB web page (<a href="http://beta.schistodb.net/schistodb/help.jsp"  target="_blank">Contact Us!</a>).
<br><br>
SchistoDB, like the other ApiDB/EuPathDB sites, offers researchers a plethora of  tools for genomic data mining.  In addition to BLAST and pattern/motif similarity searches, users can identify these three schistosoma species' genes by genomic position; common name or keyword; gene attributes such as gene type and exon number; physical characteristics of predicted proteins such as molecular weight and secondary structure;  predicted function from Gene Ontology and EC enzyme number annotation;  and cellular location.  In addition, SchistoDB contains pre-computed phylogenetic trees for proteins with homologues in other eukaryotic genomes.
<br><br>
Regards,
<br>
The SchistoDB team


          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


</xmlAnswer>

