<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE xml [
  <!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"> 
  <!ENTITY lt   "&#60;"> 
  <!ENTITY gt   "&#62;">
  <!ENTITY sl   "&#47;">
]>

<xmlAnswer>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">General Information</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">generalinfo</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
PlasmoDB is a genome database for the genus <i>Plasmodium</i>, a set of single-celled eukaryotic pathogens that cause human and animal diseases, including malaria.
<br><br>
Please check our annual <a href="http://workshop.eupathdb.org/current/index.php?page=schedule">EuPathDB Workshop at UGA</a> exercises to see the scope of data and functionality in our sites.  


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Citing Data Providers</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">citingproviders</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
Much of the data in PlasmoDB is provided by independent researchers.  For a list of the data integrated into PlasmoDB and the related publications see <a href="app/answer/DatasetQuestions.AllDatasets" class="blue"> Data Sets</a>.  Please cite the authors/providers when you use their data. 
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Advisors</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">advisors</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

Each project in EuPathDB benefits from the advice and mentoring of people from each specific community.
<br><br>


<b>PlasmoDB</b><br><br>
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
<li>John Adams (University of South Florida, USA)
<li>Stuart Ralph (University of Melbourne, Australia)
<li>Akhil Vaidya (Drexel University, USA)
<li>Chris Janse (Leiden University Medical Center, The Netherlands)
<li>Shahid Khan (Leiden University Medical Center, The Netherlands)
</ul></div>
</ul></div>
<br>
<b>Previous Advisors</b><br><br>
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
<li>Andy Waters (University of Glasgow, United Kingdom)
</ul></div>
<br>


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
PlasmoDB is a member of pathogen-databases that are housed under 
the NIAID-funded <a href="http://www.eupathdb.org">EuPathDB</a> 
Bioinformatics Resource Center (BRC) umbrella. The EuPathDB team is 
mainly distributed between the University of Pennsylvania in 
Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and the University of Georgia in Athens, 
Georgia.
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>



 

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Data Access Policy</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">use</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">The data at this site is provided freely for public use, through the contributions of many researchers including those involved in generating the genome sequences. The data is not guaranteed to be accurate as it often reflects the results of ongoing research. When using data obtained from PlasmoDB, it is important to cite the original publications and contributors of that data and PlasmoDB. Please see Citing PlasmoDB below.
</attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Citing PlasmoDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">citing</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
When citing PlasmoDB itself, please use:
<br><br>
<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/sites/entrez?db=pubmed&cmd=search&term=18957442">
PlasmoDB: a functional genomic database for malaria parasites.</a> Nucleic Acids Res. 2008 Oct 31. Aurrecoechea C, et al.

<br><br>Much of the data in PlasmoDB is provided by independent researchers.  Please cite them if you use their data.  For a list of the data integrated into PlasmoDB and the related publications please see <a href="app/answer/DatasetQuestions.AllDatasets" class="blue"> Data Sets</a>.
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>



</xmlAnswer>
