<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<xmlAnswer>

<!--
   <record>
       <attribute name="headline"></attribute>
       <attribute name="date"></attribute>
       <attribute name="tag"></attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
--> 


<record>
       <attribute name="headline"><![CDATA[AmoebaDB 1.0 released]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">15 March 2010 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">amoeba0310_news
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[

<span style="font-weight: bold;">We are pleased to announce the release of AmoebaDB 1.0<br> 
</span><br> 
We are pleased to announced the full release of AmoebaDB 1.0 
(<a href="http://amoebadb.org">http://amoebadb.org</a> or <a href="http://amebadb.org">http://amebadb.org</a>). &nbsp;<br> 
Leveraging bioinformatics infrastructure developed in the context of the EuPathDB project (including PlasmoDB, etc), this resource 
incorporates genome sequence and annotation from the Pathema project. &nbsp;
<span style="font-weight: bold;"><br><br>
Highlights include:</span>
<br><br> 
<ul> 
 <li><span style="font-weight: bold;">Sequence and annotation for</span> <i>Entamoeba histolytica, E. dispar and E. invadens</i>.</span></li> 
 <li><span style="font-weight: bold;">Genome sequence alignments</span>, permitting comparative genomic analysis of synteny between <i>Entamoeba</i> species.</li> 
 <li><span style="font-weight: bold;">Expressed sequence tag data</span> for <i>E.&nbsp;histolytica</i> and <i> E. dispar.</i></li> 
 <li><span style="font-weight: bold;">'User Comments'</span> may be added to any gene page, enhancing available annotation. 
        Such comments become immediately visible and searchable by others.</li> 
 <li><span style="font-weight: bold;">Identification of genes</span> based on text terms, ID #, GO terms, EC #, chromosomal location, BLAST, 
        sequence features (length/MW, exons, signal sequences, Pfam domains, user-defined motifs), orthology, etc. </li> 
 <li><span style="font-weight: bold;">Support for integrated searches</span>, via the 'search strategy builder'. &nbsp;Strategies can be stored and shared 
       with others by logging into AmoebaDB. For an example, <a href="http://amoebadb.org/amoeba/im.do?s=aed2d725b224ff13"><b>open this sample strategy</b></a> 
       that combines multiple searches, in your browser.</li>
</ul>
<br><br>
<span style="font-weight: bold;">***<a href="https://mail.pcbi.upenn.edu/mailman/listinfo/eupathdb_testers">Sign up to be a EuPathDB feature evaluator:
</a
>***<br><br>
</span> 
<div style="margin-left: 20px;">
We welcome you to <a href="https://mail.pcbi.upenn.edu/mailman/listinfo/eupathdb_testers">*sign up* to be an early evaluator</a>
 of new features on the EuPathDB sites.  This will be an opportunity for you to help us refine and improve features early in the development process.  
Signing up is easy.  Evaluating will require minimal effort on your part, 
typically in the form of answering specific questions, testing and rendering your opinion.
</div>
 ]]>
       </attribute>

</record>


<record>
       <attribute name="headline">EuPathDB Driving Biological Projects</attribute>
       <attribute name="date">04 February 2010 15:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">eupath_dbp_2010</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[<body>
The NIAID-funded Eukaryotic Pathogen Genome Database
(<a href="http://eupathdb.org">EuPathDB.org</a>) invites proposals for Driving Biological
Projects (DBPs) focused on one or more of the eukaryotic
pathogens supported by this Bioinformatics Resource Center
(BRC). We anticipate making two awards of up to $600K each
by July 1, 2010 (a second round of solicitations is expected
in 2012).<i> A two page Letter of Intent (LOI) is due Feb 28,
following which full applications will be solicited by
invitation only, with a deadline of March 31.</i>  
<a href="http://eupathdb.org/common/EuPathDB_DBP_announcement.pdf">
Click here to
download the RFP</a>.
</body>
          ]]>
       </attribute>
</record>

</xmlAnswer>
