<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE xml [
  <!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"> 
  <!ENTITY lt   "&#60;"> 
  <!ENTITY gt   "&#62;">
  <!ENTITY sl   "&#47;">
]>

<xmlAnswer>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">General Information</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">generalinfo</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
<![CDATA[
TriTrypDB is an integrated genomic and functional genomic database for 
pathogens of the family <i>Trypanosomatidae</i>, including organisms in both 
<i>Leishmania</i> and <i>Trypanosoma</i> genera. TriTrypDB and its continued 
development are possible through the collaborative efforts between <a 
href="http://www.eupathdb.org">EuPathDB</a>, <a href="http://www.genedb.org 
"> GeneDB </a> and colleagues at the Seattle Biomedical Research 
Institute (<a href="http://www.sbri.org">SBRI</a>).
]]>

</attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
Funding for TriTrypDB development and enhanced annotation of 
<i>kinetoplastid</i> parasites is provided by coordinated grants from the <a 
href="http://www.gatesfoundation.org/">Bill & Melinda Gates 
Foundation</a> and the <a href="http:// 
www.wellcome.ac.uk/">Wellcome Trust</a>.<br>

TriTrypDB joins the family of pathogen-databases that are housed under 
the NIAID-funded <a href="http://www.eupathdb.org">EuPathDB</a> 
Bioinformatics Resource Center (BRC) umbrella. The EuPathDB team is 
mainly distributed between the University of Pennsylvania in 
Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and the University of Georgia in Athens, 
Georgia.
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Organisms included in TriTrypDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">organisms</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
<ul>
<li><i>Trypanosoma brucei</i></li>
<li><i>Trypanosoma cruzi</i></li>
<li><i>Leishmania major</i></li>
<li><i>Leishmania infantum</i></li>
<li><i>Leishmania braziliensis</i></li>
</ul>
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="title">How to use this resource</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">use</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
TriTrypDB integrates multiple genomic-scale data types in a manner 
that enables the database user to computationally ask biologically 
relevant questions. Data may be accessed by interrogating TriTrypDB 
using any of the multiple available questions -- Please visit our 
tutorial and FAQ sections for more information.

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


<record>
       <attribute name="title">How to cite us</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">citing</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
Please use the following URL when referring to TriTrypDB: http://TriTrypDB.org
 <br><br>
Also, the following reference can be used to cite EuPathDB resources:<br><br>
Aurrecoechea, C., M. Heiges, H. Wang, Z. Wang, S. Fischer, P. Rhodes, J. Miller, E. Kraemer, C. J. Stoeckert, Jr., D. S. Roos, and J. C. Kissinger. 2007. ApiDB: integrated resources for the apicomplexan bioinformatics resource center. Nucleic Acids Research 35:D427-30. (PMID 17098930).


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

<record>
       <attribute name="title">Understanding Download Files</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">download</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
Coming Soon.


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

<record>
       <attribute name="title">Documents and Protocols</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">doc-prot</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
We are interested in including documents and protocols that are useful   
for the TriTryp community.  Please send us your suggestions by   
clicking <a href="help.jsp" target="_blank" onClick="poptastic(this.href); return false;">here</a>.


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

</xmlAnswer>
