<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xmlAnswer>

<!-- NOTE:  the date attribute must be of the form:  22 April 2009 15:00 -->
<!--
   <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date"></attribute>
       <attribute name="tag"></attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
-->
<record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
            <b>Working with Parasite Database Resources Workshop (April 17-21, 2010)</b>
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
         13 November 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
         HinxtonWorkShop
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[<big><br>
We are pleased to announce a workshop taught as part of a collaboration between the Pathogen Genomics Group 
(Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute, UK), the Eukaryotic Pathogen Bioinformatics Resource Center 
(University of Georgia and University of Pennsylvania, US), and the Seattle Biomedical Research Institute (US). 
This residential workshop aims to provide experimental biologists with hands-on experience in 
genomic-scale data analysis, including genome browsers and comparison tools, methods for 
data integration, and resources for sophisticated data mining.
Many examples and exercises will be drawn from the kinetoplastida, including <i>Leishmania spp.</i>, 
<i>Trypanosoma brucei</i>, and <i>Trypanosoma cruzi</i>, although applicants working on other protozoan 
parasites will also benefit.<br><br>

<span style="font-weight: bold;"><span
 style="color: red;">!!!!!</span>Application Deadline
is December 18th 2009<span style="color: red;">!!!!!!</span></span>
<br><br>

<b>For registration and additional information (including scholarships) please click <a href="http://www.wellcome.ac.uk/Education-resources/Courses-and-conferences/Advanced-Courses/Courses/WTX057366.htm">here</a> (Note: you will be diverted to and external site).
</b><br><br>
As usual, if you have any questions please send us an <a href="mailto:help@eupathdb.org">Email</a>. 

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
<record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
            TriTrypDB published in Nucleic Acid Research
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
         21 October 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
         Tritryppub
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[<big><br>
We are pleased to announce the publication of a paper
introducing&nbsp;TriTrypDB. &nbsp;The paper entitled
"TriTrypDB: a functional genomic resource for the Trypanosomatidae" is
available <a
 href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/gkp851">here</a>
as an advance access publication.</big><span
 style="font-weight: bold;"><br>
<br>
</span><span style="font-style: italic;">This
article may be used to cite the TriTrypDB resource in your publications.
&nbsp;To download this reference to your citation manager please
click </span><a style="font-style: italic;"
 href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/citmgr?gca=nar;gkp851v1">here</a><span
 style="font-style: italic;">.</span>
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
<record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
            TriTrypDB 1.2 released
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
         25 September 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
         Tritryp909news
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[<b>We are pleased to
announce the release of TriTrypDB 1.2</b><br>
<br>
<u>New Data:</u><br>
<ul>
  <li>New <il>T. cruzi</il>
genome assembly as described in the publication by <a
 href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19486522">Weatherly</a>
and colleagues.</li>
  <li><il>T. cruzi </il>reservosome
proteomics data (<a
 href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19288526">Sant'Anna&nbsp;<il>et. al.</il></a>).</li>
  <li><il>T. cruzi </il>insect
form proteomics data (<a
 href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19374451">Cordero </a><a
 href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19374451"><il>et. al.</il></a>).</li>
  <li><il>L. infantum</il>
proteomics data set from Dr. Marc Ouellette's group (provided
prepublication).</li>
  <li>Genome-wide analysis of mRNA abundance in two life-cycle
stages of <il>T. brucei </il>and
identification of trans-splicing and polyadenylation sites. RNA-seq (T.
Nicolai Siegel, Doeke R. Hekstra, Xuning Wang, Scott Dewell and George
A. M. Cross, provided prepublication) -- this data can be viewed as
tracks in the genome browser, click here for an example.</li>
</ul>
<u>New/Updated
Features:</u><br>
<ul>
  <li>Now after you perform a BlastN against genomic sequence you
can
link from the blast output to the correct coordinates in the genome
browser.&nbsp; This allows you to explore annotation and other
functional
data in relation to your BLAST hits.</li>
  <li>The type ahead feature has been implemented for GO term, EC
number and Interpro domain searches.</li>
  <li>You can now edit or delete your user comments.</li>
  <li>You can now modify your user profile, change your password
or your email address.</li>
</ul>
Please also note that the parent portal site <a
 href="http://eupathdb.org">EuPathDB</a> has just been
updated, offering you the ability to explore results across organisms.<br>
<br>
Sincerely,<br>
<br>
The EuPathDB and GeneDB teams.

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
<record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
            TriTrypDB 1.1 released
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
         14 July 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
         tritrypdb_release11
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
We are pleased to announce the release TriTrypDB 1.1 
<br><br>Highlights include:<br><br>
<ul>
<li>The <i>L. tarentolae</i> genome has been provided by the CIHR Group on host pathogen interactions and is available for similarity searches and browsing for open reading frames and BLASTX alignments against the NR protein database.
<li>A microarray experiment examining the axenic promastigote-to-amastigote differentiation of <i>L. donovani</i> was provided by researchers at the Seattle Biomedical Research Institute and Technion Institute and is available for query and display on record pages.
<li>A new search strategy interface that enables users to more easily construct complex searches is released for the first time in TriTrypDB 1.1.
<li>&#39;User Comments&#39; have been updated to enable submission of supporting evidence including pubmed identifiers and images (or other files).  Comments may be added to any gene or sequence page, enhancing available annotation.  Such comments are visible and searchable by others, and are automatically forwarded to the annotation team for incorporation into the official annotation<br>
<li>Files can now be uploaded and provided to the community via TriTrypDB.
</ul>
<br>
Please click on the &#39;Contact Us&#39; link at the bottom of each page to indicate anything that might help to make the site better: bugs, help requests, features that are unclear or take too long to run, suggestions for additional tools or datasets that might be useful to incorporate, etc.  Where appropriate, please also add to the &#39;User Comments&#39; on each gene page, noting inaccurate (or accurate) gene models, phenotype information, expression data, clone availability, etc.
<p>
The previous version of TriTrypDB may still be accessed <a href='http://old.tritrypdb.org'>here</a>.
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
           253 genes updated in GeneDB since KCMB meeting
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
         27 May 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
         27May2009TriTrypDB11
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
We received many user comments during the KCMB meeting and following.  Many of these have already been examined by TriTrypDB curators (at GeneDB, SBRI and UGA) and incorporated into the official annotation. 253 genes have been modified since the meeting resulting in a total of 710 genes that have been updated since this current build of TriTrypDB. <b><a href="showSummary.do?questionFullName=GeneQuestions.GenesWithUpdatedAnnotation">Click here</a></b> to see the complete list of genes that have been re-annotated since December 1, 2008.
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
            Beta-release of TriTrypDB 1.1
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
         24 April 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
         24Apr2009TriTrypDB11
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
We are pleased to announce the availability of a beta-release version of TriTrypDB 1.1, accessible at <a href="http://beta.TriTrypDB.org">http://beta.TriTrypDB.org</a>.  Feel free to forward this link to others.  <br><br>Highlights include:<br><br>
<ul>
<li>The <i>L. tarentolae</i> genome has been provided by the CIHR Group on host pathogen interactions and is available for similarity searches and browsing for open reading frames and BLASTX alignments against the NR protein database.
<li>A microarray experiment examining the axenic promastigote-to-amastigote differentiation of <i>L. donovani</i> was provided by researchers at the Seattle Biomedical Research Institute and Technion Institute and is available for query and display on record pages.
<li>A new search strategy interface that enables users to more easily construct complex searches is released for the first time in TriTrypDB 1.1.
<li>&#39;User Comments&#39; have been updated to enable submission of supporting evidence including pubmed identifiers and images (or other files).  Comments may be added to any gene or sequence page, enhancing available annotation.  Such comments are visible and searchable by others, and are automatically forwarded to the annotation team for incorporation into the official annotation<br>
<li>Files can now be uploaded and provided to the community via TriTrypDB.
</ul>
<br>
By providing access to TriTrypDB 1.1 prior to its official release, we hope to obtain valuable feedback to facilitate the debugging process, in addition to making new data and functionality available to the community as early as possible.  Please click on the &#39;Contact Us&#39; link at the bottom of each page to indicate anything that might help to make the site better: bugs, help requests, features that are unclear or take too long to run, suggestions for additional tools or datasets that might be useful to incorporate, etc.  Where appropriate, please also add to the &#39;User Comments&#39; on each gene page, noting inaccurate (or accurate) gene models, phenotype information, expression data, clone availability, etc.
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
           457 updated annotations available in GeneDB
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
         22 April 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
         22Apr2009TriTrypDB11
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
Annotation of the Kinetoplastida is ramping up again as part of the collaborative efforts of EuPathDB and GeneDB.  Annotations are being carried out at the Welcome Trust Sanger Center, the Seattle Biomedical Research Institute and the University of Georgia. <b><a href="showSummary.do?questionFullName=GeneQuestions.GenesWithUpdatedAnnotation">Click here</a></b> to see the list of genes that have been re-annotated since December 1, 2008 when this current build of TriTrypDB was started.
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

     <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
        TriTrypDB 1.0 Released
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
       06 February 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
       6Feb2009TriTrypDB10
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
We are pleased to announce the first release of TriTrypDB 1.0, a new bioinformatics resource for kinetoplastid parasites.
<p>
Leveraging bioinformatics infrastructure developed in the context of the EuPathDB project (including PlasmoDB, etc), this resource incorporates genome sequence and annotation from the GeneDB project, along with additional datasets generously provided by many research laboratories.
<p>
Highlights include:
<ul>
<li>Sequence and annotation for <i>Leishmania braziliensis</i>, <i>L. infantum</i>, <i>L. major</i>, <i>Trypanosoma brucei</i> and <i>Trypanosoma cruzi</i>.</li>
<li>Genome sequence alignments, permitting comparative genomic analysis of synteny (<i>T. cruzi</i> scaffolds assembled into virtual chromosomes, distinguishing 'Esmeraldo' and 'non-Esmeraldo' haplotypes).</li>
<li>Expression data, including ESTs and proteomics evidence for <i>L. infantum</i>, <i>T. brucei</i> and <i>T. cruzi</i> (from several laboratories, much of it made available prior to publication).</li>
<li>Phenotypic information, including manually curated RNAi knock-down phenotypes for <i>T. brucei</i> from TrypanoFAN and the published literature, aiding functional analysis and the validation of essential targets.</li>
<li>'User Comments' may be added to any gene page, enhancing available annotation.  Such comments are visible and searchable by others, and will be automatically forwarded to the annotation team.</li>
<li>Identification of genes based on text terms, ID #, GO terms, EC #, chromosomal location, BLAST, sequence features (length/MW, introns, signal sequences, Pfam domains, user-defined motifs), structure, epitopes, orthology, functional information, etc.</li>
<li>Support for integrated searches, via 'Query History', such as:</li>
  <ul>
  <li>"Find all <i>T. brucei</i> genes for which siRNA-mediated knock-downs yield a lethal phenotype"</li>
  <li>"Find <i>L. major</i> kinases without human orthologs that are supported by expression evidence in any kinetoplastid parasite"</li>
  </ul>
</ul>
<p>
Look for TriTrypDB at the Kinetoplastid Molecular Cell Biology Meeting in Woods Hole, MA (26-29 April 2009; registration deadline 6 March).
<p>
This integrated kinetoplastid bioinformatics resource has been made possible by support from NIAID (EuPathDB), the Wellcome Trust (GeneDB), and the Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation (TriTrypDB).

 ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


     <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
        Beta-release of TriTrypDB 1.0
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
       23 January 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
       23January2009TriTrypDBbeta
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
We are pleased to announce the availability of a beta-release version of TriTrypDB, accessible at <a href="http://beta.TriTrypDB.org">http://beta.TriTrypDB.org</a>.  Feel free to forward this link to others.  <br><br>Highlights include:<br><br>


&#x2023; Sequence and annotation for <i>Leishmania braziliensis</i>, <i>L. infantum</i>, <i>L. major</i>, <i>Trypanosoma brucei</i> and <i>T. cruzi</i>.  All current annotations from <a href="http://www.genedb.org">GeneDB</a> have been incorporated into TriTrypDB 1.0.<br>
&#x2023; Genes may be queried based on gene IDs, text terms, EC numbers, GO terms, sequence features (length, introns, signal sequences, Pfam domains), etc.<br>
&#x2023; Genes and sequences may also be interrogated based on BLAST similarity, user-defined motifs, etc.<br>
&#x2023; <i>T. cruzi</i> scaffolds have been assembled into virtual chromosomes, distinguishing the 'Esmeraldo' and 'non-Esmeraldo' haplotypes.<br>
&#x2023; Alignments between all available genome sequences, permitting comparative genomic analysis of synteny and convenient downloads of aligned sequences.<br>
&#x2023; Expression data, including Expressed Sequence Tag (EST) evidence, and proteomics evidence for <i>L. infantum</i>, <i>T. brucei</i> and <i>T. cruzi</i> (from several laboratories, much of it kindly made available prior to publication).<br>
&#x2023; Phenotypic information from <a href="http://www.genedb.org">GeneDB</a>, including manually curated RNAi knock-down phenotypes for <i>T. brucei</i> from <a href="http://trypanofan.path.cam.ac.uk/trypanofan/main/">TrypanoFAN</a> and the published literature, aiding functional analysis and the validation of essential targets.<br>
&#x2023; Identification of orthologs, permiting inferences for one species based on evidence from others.  For example you might want to identify <i>L. major</i> genes that are orthologs of essential <i>T. brucei</i> kinases, or <i>T. cruzi</i> proteins supported by expression evidence in any kinetoplastid species.<br>
&#x2023; &#39;User Comments&#39; may be added to any gene page, enhancing available annotation.  Such comments are visible and searchable by others, and will be automatically forwarded to the annotation team.<br><br>

By providing access to TriTrypDB prior to its official release, we hope to obtain valuable feedback to facilitate the debugging process, in addition to making this resource available to the community as early as possible.  Please click on the &#39;Contact Us&#39; link at the bottom of each page to indicate anything that might help to make the site better: bugs, help requests, features that are unclear or take too long to run, suggestions for additional tools or datasets that might be useful to incorporate, etc.  Where appropriate, please also add to the &#39;User Comments&#39; on each gene page, noting inaccurate (or accurate) gene models, expression data, clone availability, etc.

 ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

<record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         Kinetoplastid Molecular Cell Biology Meeting III
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
       20 January 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
       20January2009KMCBMIII
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
The 3rd kinetoplastid molecular cell biology meeting will be held from April 26-29th, 2009 in Woods Hole, Massachusetts, USA. For more information click <a href="http://www.mbl.edu/kmcb/2009/index.php">here</a>.
 ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         EuPathDB to take on the kinetoplastida
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
       1 November 2008 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
       1November2008GatesFoundation
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[

We are pleased to report
an award from the <a href="http://www.gatesfoundation.org">Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation</a> in support of a
TriTrypDB component of the <a href="http://eupathdb.org/">EuPathDB</a> family of databases,
encompassing <i>Leishmania</i> species, <i>Trypanosoma brucei</i>, and
<i>Trypanosoma cruzi</i>.  A coordinated award from the<a href="http://www.wellcome.ac.uk/"> Wellcome Trust</a>
will permit enhanced annotation of kinetoplastid parasites. 
These projects represent a collaborative effort between the
GeneDB team (at the Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute), colleagues
at the <a href="http://www.sbri.org/">Seattle Biomedical Research Institute</a>, and the EuPathDB
team -- an NIAID-supported Bioinformatics Resource Center. Look
for the first release of TriTrypDB in Jan 2009!

 ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

</xmlAnswer>

