<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xmlAnswer>
<!--
   <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date"></attribute>
       <attribute name="tag"></attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
-->

     <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
        TriTrypDB 1.0 Released
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
       06 February 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
       6Feb2009TriTrypDB10
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
We are pleased to announce the first release of TriTrypDB 1.0, a new bioinformatics resource for kinetoplastid parasites.
<p>
Leveraging bioinformatics infrastructure developed in the context of the EuPathDB project (including PlasmoDB, etc), this resource incorporates genome sequence and annotation from the GeneDB project, along with additional datasets generously provided by many research laboratories.
<p>
Highlights include:
<ul>
<li>Sequence and annotation for <i>Leishmania braziliensis</i>, <i>L. infantum</i>, <i>L. major</i>, <i>Trypanosoma brucei</i> and <i>Trypanosoma cruzi</i>.</li>
<li>Genome sequence alignments, permitting comparative genomic analysis of synteny (<i>T. cruzi</i> scaffolds assembled into virtual chromosomes, distinguishing 'Esmeraldo' and 'non-Esmeraldo' haplotypes).</li>
<li>Expression data, including ESTs and proteomics evidence for <i>L. infantum</i>, <i>T. brucei</i> and <i>T. cruzi</i> (from several laboratories, much of it made available prior to publication).</li>
<li>Phenotypic information, including manually curated RNAi knock-down phenotypes for <i>T. brucei</i> from TrypanoFAN and the published literature, aiding functional analysis and the validation of essential targets.</li>
<li>'User Comments' may be added to any gene page, enhancing available annotation.  Such comments are visible and searchable by others, and will be automatically forwarded to the annotation team.</li>
<li>Identification of genes based on text terms, ID #, GO terms, EC #, chromosomal location, BLAST, sequence features (length/MW, introns, signal sequences, Pfam domains, user-defined motifs), structure, epitopes, orthology, functional information, etc.</li>
<li>Support for integrated searches, via 'Query History', such as:</li>
  <ul>
  <li>"Find all <i>T. brucei</i> genes for which siRNA-mediated knock-downs yield a lethal phenotype"</li>
  <li>"Find <i>L. major</i> kinases without human orthologs that are supported by expression evidence in any kinetoplastid parasite"</li>
  </ul>
</ul>
<p>
Look for TriTrypDB at the Kinetoplastid Molecular Cell Biology Meeting in Woods Hole, MA (26-29 April 2009; registration deadline 6 March).
<p>
This integrated kinetoplastid bioinformatics resource has been made possible by support from NIAID (EuPathDB), the Wellcome Trust (GeneDB), and the Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation (TriTrypDB).

 ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


     <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
        Beta-release of TriTrypDB 1.0
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
       23 January 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
       23January2009TriTrypDBbeta
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
We are pleased to announce the availability of a beta-release version of TriTrypDB, accessible at <a href="http://beta.TriTrypDB.org">http://beta.TriTrypDB.org</a>.  Feel free to forward this link to others.  <br><br>Highlights include:<br><br>


&#x2023; Sequence and annotation for <i>Leishmania braziliensis</i>, <i>L. infantum</i>, <i>L. major</i>, <i>Trypanosoma brucei</i> and <i>T. cruzi</i>.  All current annotations from <a href="http://www.genedb.org">GeneDB</a> have been incorporated into TriTrypDB 1.0.<br>
&#x2023; Genes may be queried based on gene IDs, text terms, EC numbers, GO terms, sequence features (length, introns, signal sequences, Pfam domains), etc.<br>
&#x2023; Genes and sequences may also be interrogated based on BLAST similarity, user-defined motifs, etc.<br>
&#x2023; <i>T. cruzi</i> scaffolds have been assembled into virtual chromosomes, distinguishing the 'Esmeraldo' and 'non-Esmeraldo' haplotypes.<br>
&#x2023; Alignments between all available genome sequences, permitting comparative genomic analysis of synteny and convenient downloads of aligned sequences.<br>
&#x2023; Expression data, including Expressed Sequence Tag (EST) evidence, and proteomics evidence for <i>L. infantum</i>, <i>T. brucei</i> and <i>T. cruzi</i> (from several laboratories, much of it kindly made available prior to publication).<br>
&#x2023; Phenotypic information from <a href="http://www.genedb.org">GeneDB</a>, including manually curated RNAi knock-down phenotypes for <i>T. brucei</i> from <a href="http://trypanofan.path.cam.ac.uk/trypanofan/main/">TrypanoFAN</a> and the published literature, aiding functional analysis and the validation of essential targets.<br>
&#x2023; Identification of orthologs, permiting inferences for one species based on evidence from others.  For example you might want to identify <i>L. major</i> genes that are orthologs of essential <i>T. brucei</i> kinases, or <i>T. cruzi</i> proteins supported by expression evidence in any kinetoplastid species.<br>
&#x2023; &#39;User Comments&#39; may be added to any gene page, enhancing available annotation.  Such comments are visible and searchable by others, and will be automatically forwarded to the annotation team.<br><br>

By providing access to TriTrypDB prior to its official release, we hope to obtain valuable feedback to facilitate the debugging process, in addition to making this resource available to the community as early as possible.  Please click on the &#39;Contact Us&#39; link at the bottom of each page to indicate anything that might help to make the site better: bugs, help requests, features that are unclear or take too long to run, suggestions for additional tools or datasets that might be useful to incorporate, etc.  Where appropriate, please also add to the &#39;User Comments&#39; on each gene page, noting inaccurate (or accurate) gene models, expression data, clone availability, etc.

 ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

<record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         Kinetoplastid Molecular Cell Biology Meeting III
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
       20 January 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
       20January2009KMCBMIII
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
The 3rd kinetoplastid molecular cell biology meeting will be held from April 26-29th, 2009 in Woods Hole, Massachusetts, USA. For more information click <a href="http://www.mbl.edu/kmcb/2009/index.php">here</a>.
 ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

<record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         The 4th World Congress on Leishmaniasis
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
       20 January 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
       20January20094thWorldCongressonLeishmaniasis 
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
The 4th World Congress on Leishmaniasis will be held from February 3rd -7th, 2009 in Lucknow, India.  For more information click <a href="http://www.worldleish4.org/">here</a>.
 ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         EuPathDB to take on the kinetoplastida
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
       1 November 2008 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
       1November2008GatesFoundation
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[

We are pleased to report
an award from the <a href="http://www.gatesfoundation.org">Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation</a> in support of a
TriTrypDB component of the <a href="http://eupathdb.org/">EuPathDB</a> family of databases,
encompassing <i>Leishmania</i> species, <i>Trypanosoma brucei</i>, and
<i>Trypanosoma cruzi</i>.  A coordinated award from the<a href="http://www.wellcome.ac.uk/"> Wellcome Trust</a>
will permit enhanced annotation of kinetoplastid parasites. 
These projects represent a collaborative effort between the
GeneDB team (at the Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute), colleagues
at the <a href="http://www.sbri.org/">Seattle Biomedical Research Institute</a>, and the EuPathDB
team -- an NIAID-supported Bioinformatics Resource Center. Look
for the first release of TriTrypDB in Jan 2009!

 ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

</xmlAnswer>

