<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE xml [
  <!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"> 
  <!ENTITY lt   "&#60;"> 
  <!ENTITY gt   "&#62;">
  <!ENTITY sl   "&#47;">
]>

<xmlAnswer>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">General Information</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">generalinfo</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
<![CDATA[
MicrosporidiaDB belongs to the <a href="http://www.eupathdb.org">EuPathDB</a> family of databases and is an integrated genomic and functional genomic 
database for the phylum <i>Microsporidia</i>.  In its first iteration (released in early 2010), MicrosporidiaDB contains the genomes of two  <i>Encephalitozoon</i> species 
(see below).  
MicrosporidiaDB integrates whole genome sequence and annotation and will rapidly expand to include experimental data and environmental isolate sequences 
provided by community researchers . The database includes supplemental bioinformatics analyses and a web interface for data-mining.
<br><br>
For a list of the data integrated into MicrosporidiaDB and the related publications please see <a href="app/answer/DatasetQuestions.AllDatasets" class="blue"> Data Sets</a>.
<br><br>
Please check our annual <a href="http://workshop.eupathdb.org/current/index.php?page=schedule">EuPathDB Workshop at UGA</a> exercises to see the scope of data and functionality in our sites.  

]]>
</attribute>
   </record>

<record>
       <attribute name="title">Citing Data Providers</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">citingproviders</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
Much of the data in MicrosporidiaDB is provided by independent researchers.  For a list of the data integrated into MicrosporidiaDB and the related publications see <a href="app/answer/DatasetQuestions.AllDatasets" class="blue"> Data Sets</a>.  Please cite the authors/providers when you use their data. 
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Scientific Advisory Team</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">advisors</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
EuPathDB databases rely heavily on community input.  Each project in EuPathDB benefits from the advice and mentoring of members from each specific community. 
We hold monthly organism calls for each of our databases with members of the scientific advisory teams and others from the community.  
Anyone interested in joining one of these conference calls is encouraged to contact us.  While monthly conference calls for MicrosporidiaDB are already underway, 
a specific scientific advisory team as not yet been assembled.
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
MicrosporidiaDB is a member of pathogen-databases that are housed under 
the NIAID-funded <a href="http://www.eupathdb.org">EuPathDB</a> 
Bioinformatics Resource Center (BRC) umbrella. The EuPathDB team is 
mainly distributed between the University of Pennsylvania in 
Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and the University of Georgia in Athens, 
Georgia.
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>



 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Data Access Policy</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">use</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
The data at this site is provided freely for public use, through
the contributions of many researchers including those involved in
generating the genome sequences. The data is not guaranteed to be
accurate as it often reflects the results of ongoing research.
When using data obtained from any EuPathDB project, it is important to cite
the original publications and contributors of that data. 

Please see Citing MicrosporidiaDB below.

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


<record>
       <attribute name="title">Citing MicrosporidiaDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">citing</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
When citing MicrosporidiaDB itself, please use:

<br><br>
<b><a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20974635">AmoebaDB and MicrosporidiaDB: functional genomic resources for Amoebozoa and Microsporidia species.</a>

<br><br>Much of the data in MicrosporidiaDB is provided by independent researchers.  Please cite them if you use their data.  For a list of the data integrated into MicrosporidiaDB and the related publications please see <a href="app/answer/DatasetQuestions.AllDatasets" class="blue"> Data Sets</a>.


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

<!--    
<record>
       <attribute name="title">Documents and Publications</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">docs_pubs</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
We are interested in including documents and protocols that are useful   
for the CryptoDB community.  Please send us your suggestions by   
clicking <a href="help.jsp" target="_blank" onClick="poptastic(this.href); return false;">here</a>.


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>
-->

<!--
<record>
       <attribute name="title">Additional Information</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag"></attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[




   ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>
-->

</xmlAnswer>
