<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE xml [
  <!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"> 
  <!ENTITY lt   "&#60;"> 
  <!ENTITY gt   "&#62;">
  <!ENTITY sl   "&#47;">
]>

<xmlAnswer>

    <record>
       <attribute name="title">General Information</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">generalinfo</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
For a list of the data integrated into PiroplasmaDB and the related publications please see <a href="app/search/dataset/AllDatasets/result" class="blue"> Data Sets</a>.
<br><br>
Please check our annual <a href="http://workshop.eupathdb.org/current/index.php?page=schedule">EuPathDB Workshop at UGA</a> exercises to see the scope of data and functionality in our sites.  

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


<record>
       <attribute name="title">Citing Data Providers</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">citingproviders</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
Much of the data in PiroplamaDB is provided by independent researchers.  For a list of the data integrated into PiroplasmaDB and the related publications see <a href="app/search/dataset/AllDatasets/result" class="blue"> Data Sets</a>.  Please cite the authors/providers when you use their data. 
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Advisors</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">advisors</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

EuPathDB databases rely heavily on community input.  Each project in EuPathDB benefits from the advice and mentoring of members from each specific community. 
We hold monthly organism calls for each of our databases with members of the scientific advisory teams and others from the community.  
Anyone interested in joining one of these conference calls is encouraged to contact us.  
<!-- While monthly conference calls for PiroplasmaDB are already underway, 
a specific scientific advisory team as not yet been assembled.-->

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
PiroplasmaDB is a member of pathogen-databases that are housed under 
the NIAID-funded <a href="http://www.eupathdb.org">EuPathDB</a> 
Bioinformatics Resource Center (BRC) umbrella. The EuPathDB team is mainly distributed between the 
<a href="https://www.upenn.edu">University of Pennsylvania</a> Philadelphia, USA  
the <a href="http://www.uga.edu">University of Georgia</a>, Georgia, USA, and several members of the team are located at 
the <a href="https://www.liverpool.ac.uk">University of Liverpool</a>, United Kingdom, 
<a href="https://www.gla.ac.uk">University of Glasgow</a>, United Kingdom 
and <a href="http://www.sanger.ac.uk">The Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute</a>, United Kingdom.
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Data Access Policy</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">policy</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">The data at this site is provided freely for public use, through the contributions of many researchers including those involved in generating the genome sequences. The data is not guaranteed to be accurate as it often reflects the results of ongoing research. When using data obtained from PiroplasmaDB, it is important to cite the original publications and contributors of that data and PiroplasmaDB. Please see Citing PiroplasmaDB below.
</attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Website Privacy Policy</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">privacy</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
       We do not use or share any of your personal information for any
       purpose unrelated to the functionality of the websites; however,
       we do collect some information to help us understand how our
       sites are being used and to improve community support. See the <a
       href="/documents/EuPathDB_Website_Privacy_Policy.shtml">
       Website Privacy Policy</a> for details.
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Citing PiroplasmaDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">citing</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
When citing PiroplasmaDB itself, please use:
<br><br>
<b>EuPathDB: a portal to eukaryotic pathogen databases.</b><br>
 2010 Nucleic Acids Res. 2010 Jan;38(Database issue):D415-9. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkp941<br>
 [ <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/38/suppl_1/D415/3112291">Full text</a> ]
<br><br>
When citing EuPathDB itself, please use:
<br>
<b>EuPathDB: the eukaryotic pathogen genomics database resource.</b><br>
2017 Nucleic Acids Res. Jan 4;45(D1):D581-D591. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkw1105<br>
[ <a href="https://academic.oup.com/nar/article/45/D1/D581/2605823#51201154">Full text</a> ]

<br><br>Much of the data in PiroplasmaDB is provided by independent researchers.  Please cite them if you use their data.  For a list of the data integrated into PiroplasmaDB and the related publications please see <a href="app/search/dataset/AllDatasets/result" class="blue"> Data Sources</a>.


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

</xmlAnswer>
