<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xmlAnswer>

<!--
   <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="category"></attribute>
       <attribute name="item">
           
         <![CDATA[
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
-->



<record>
       <attribute name="headline">HostDB in Beta Released</attribute>
       <attribute name="date">30 September 2013 13:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">host1_14_news</attribute>
       <attribute name="category">release</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">
         <![CDATA[
 <body>
    <p><strong>We are pleased to announce a beta release of HostDB</strong></p>
    <p><br>
      <strong></strong></p>
    <p>HostDB is the newest addition to the Eukaryotic Pathogen databases (<strong><a
          href="http://eupathdb.org">EuPathDB</a></strong>).&nbsp;
      This resource will provide researchers with the powerful search strategy
      system to search functional data from host organisms during infection with
      parasites supported by EuPathDB.&nbsp; The beta release includes the
      following datasets:</p>
    <p><br>
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>The transcriptomes of primary murine macrophages (<em>M. musculus</em>
        C57BL6J) during infection with 25 strains of <em>Toxoplasma gondii</em>.&nbsp;
        Additional information about this genome may be viewed in the <strong><a
            href="http://hostdb.org/hostdb/getDataset.do?question=GeneQuestions.GenesByRNASeqmmusC57BL6J_Saeij_Jeroen_25_strains_rnaSeq_RSRC&amp;display=detail#3">Dataset
            section</a></strong> of HostDB.&nbsp; </li>
    </ul>
    <br>
    <ul>
      <li>Proteomic analysis of Homo Sapiens during infection with 4 <em>Toxoplasma
          gondii </em>(GT1, ME49, RH and VEG) strains.&nbsp; Additional
        information about this genome may be viewed in the <strong><a href="http://hostdb.org/hostdb/getDataset.do?question=GeneQuestions.GenesByProteomicshsapREF_quantitativeMassSpec_Wastling_Tgondii_Infection_timecourse_RSRC&amp;display=detail#5">Dataset
            section</a></strong> of HostDB.&nbsp; </li>
    </ul>
    <p>We look forward to expanding this database in data content and
      functionality.&nbsp; As with all of out community driven databases we
      encourage you to explore <strong><a href="http://hostdb.org">HostDB</a></strong>
      and provide us with you <a href="mailto:help@hostdb.org"><strong>feedback</strong></a>.&nbsp;
      </p>
    <p><br>
    </p>
    <p><em><strong>Follow</strong></em> <span style="font-weight: bold;"><span
          style="font-style: italic;">EuPathDB
          on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/EuPathDB/133123003429972">FaceBook</a></span></span><span
        style="font-weight: bold; font-style: italic;">,
        <a href="http://twitter.com/eupathdb">Twitter</a>, and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/EuPathDB">YouTube</a></span></p>
  </body>
          ]]>
       </attribute>
</record>





<record>
       <attribute name="headline">EuPathDB Annual Workshop</attribute>
       <attribute name="date">20 January 2013 15:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">eupathworkshop</attribute>
       <attribute name="category">workshop</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">
           
         <![CDATA[
 <body> 
    <p align="justify">We are pleased to announce the 8th annual EuPathDB
      workshop to be held in Athens, Georgia, USA from June 2-5, 2013.   <br />
      <br />
      Please note that the workshop expenses, in addition to room and board
      costs are covered by EuPathDB (see cost and fees section below).  <br />
      <br />
      Come learn how to effectively use EuPathDB resources and mine available
      data to help guide your research.<br />
      <br />
      <b><a href="http://workshop.eupathdb.org/current/">For more information
          and to apply, please visit: http://workshop.eupathdb.org/current/</a></b><br />
      <br />
      The workshop will cover all of our component databases (EuPathDB,
      AmoebaDB, CryptoDB, GiardiaDB, MicrosporidiaDB, PlasmoDB, PiroplasmaDB,
      ToxoDB, TrichDB, TriTrypDB and OrthoMCL), and will run from 6:00PM (18:00)
      on Sunday, June 2 to 5:00PM (17:00) on Wednesday, June 5, 2013.<br />
      <br />
      The application deadline is February 18, 2013 and the course is limited to
      30 participants.<br />
      <br />
      Who should apply:  This workshop is intended to be a 3 day thorough and
      intensive introduction to database resources that are part of the
      EuPathDB.org Bioinformatics Resource Center (EuPathDB, AmoebaDB, CryptoDB,
      GiardiaDB, MicrosporidiaDB, PlasmoDB, PiroplasmaDB, ToxoDB, TrichDB,
      TriTrypDB and OrthoMCL). The ideal candidate would have a need to become
      an expert user of one or more of these database resources and presumably
      has a bioinformatics research problem that they might work on as part of
      their training while attending the course. Preference will be given to
      applicants that are in a position to benefit most from intensive training
      and that are in a position to return to their home institution and
      transfer their newly acquired knowledge to others. Evaluation of the
      applications will focus heavily on your responses to the questions asked
      on the application page and on letters of recommendation.<br />
      <br />
      Costs and Fees: The course is free. Housing, all training materials and
      most meals are covered. Attendees are expected to provide their own
      transportation to the course and pay for a few of their meals. No travel
      funds are available. Letters of acceptance will be mailed early to
      facilitate the solicitation of outside travel funds. Hotel room charges
      will be paid by EuPathDB from June 2 through 11:00am June 6 (Note: course
      ends at 5PM on June 5). Participants traveling from abroad may be able to
      arrive a day early or stay a day late as needed to accommodate travel
      arrangements.<br />
      <br />
      For more information and to apply, please visit: <b><a href="http://workshop.eupathdb.org/current/">http://workshop.eupathdb.org/current/</a></b><br />
      <br />
      If you have any questions or concerns please email <strong><a href="mailto:help@eupathdb.org">help@eupathdb.org</a></strong><br />
    </p>
  </body>
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>








</xmlAnswer>

