<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE xml [
  <!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"> 
  <!ENTITY lt   "&#60;"> 
  <!ENTITY gt   "&#62;">
  <!ENTITY sl   "&#47;">
]>

<xmlAnswer>






<record>
       <attribute name="title">Scientific Working Group</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">swg</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">   
         <![CDATA[
EuPathDB is pleased to announce the members of the scientific working group
(SWG). The SWG provides EuPathDB with scientific oversight and 
guidance.  Members of the SWG also review the driving biological projects initiative.<br><br>

<table>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://www.fnih.org/about">Michael Gottlieb</a>, Chair<br>
Foundation for National Institutes of Health (FNIH)<br>
Broad expertise in parasitology, large integrative projects (chair)<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.sanger.ac.uk/research/faculty/mberriman/">Matt Berriman</a><br>
Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute<br>
Pathogen genomics & functional annotation<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://med.stanford.edu/profiles/John_Boothroyd/">John Boothroyd</a><br>
Stanford University<br>
Toxoplasma biology & host-pathogen interactions<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.vcu.edu/lifesci/research/res_fac_int_buck.html">Greg Buck</a><br>
Virginia Commonwealth University<br>
Pathogenomics of apicomplexan and kinetoplastid parasites<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://www.niaid.nih.gov/labsandresources/labs/aboutlabs/lmiv/Pages/PathogenesisImmun.aspx">Patrick Duffy</a><br>
National Institutes of Health (NIAID)<br>
Laboratory & clinical aspects of malaria biology<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.cgm.northwestern.edu/">Pascale Gaudet</a><br>
Northwestern University<br>
Biocuration, ontologies, DIctyostelium<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://www.paras.uzh.ch/research/microbiology.html">Adrian Hehl</a><br>
University of  Zurich<br>
Cellular and molecular biology of Giardia<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.bio21.unimelb.edu.au/group-leaders/bio-chemistry/malcolm-mcconville">Malcolm McConville</a><br>
Bio21, Melbourne University<br>
Plasmodium, Toxoplasma and Leishmania metabolomics and drug discovery<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://www.medicine.virginia.edu/clinical/departments/pathology/faculty/petri-page">Bill Petri</a><br>
University of Virginia<br>
Laboratory & clinical aspects of Entamoeba and diarrheal diseases<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.oicr.on.ca/Research/stein.htm">Lincoln Stein</a><br>
Ontario Cancer Center<br>
Bioinformatics tools & analysis<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://www.liv.ac.uk/infection-and-global-health/staff/jonathan-wastling/">Jonathan Wastling</a><br>
University of Liverpool<br>
Proteomics of apicomplexan parasites<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.einstein.yu.edu/home/faculty/profile.asp?id=4218">Louis Weiss</a><br>
Albert Einstein College of Medicine<br>
Microsporidia, Toxoplasma, and clinical microbiology<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/faculty/dyann-wirth/">Dyann Wirth</a><br>
Harvard School of Public Health<br>
Plasmodium population biology, drug discovery<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=5283487&authType=NAME_SEARCH&authToken=XrcJ&locale=en_US&srchid=2d1b49c1-ee1a-4932-8245-027b7f3bb895-0&srchindex=1&srchtotal=9&goback=%2Efps_PBCK_*1_Jennifer_Wortman&pvs=ps&trk=pp_profile_name_link">Jennifer Wortman</a><br>
Broad Institute<br>
Microbial Informatics Genome Sequencing & Analysis Program<br>
</td></tr></table>
          ]]>
       </attribute>
</record>


<record>
       <attribute name="title">Data Statistics</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">stats</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

<div id="cirbulletlist"><ul>
<li>The <a href = "/a/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.GenomeDataType">EuPathDB Data Summary</a> provides an overview of the content in EuPathDB across sites, all organisms and data types covered.
<li>The <a href="/a/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.GeneMetrics">EuPathDB Gene Metrics Table</a> summarizes the number of genes for the organisms currently available in EuPathDB, by various datatypes.
</ul></div>

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


<record>
       <attribute name="title">Understanding Downloads</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">downloads</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
There are several kinds of downloads available in a EuPathDB site:
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>

<li> Download files that we create at release time. The link to access these files is under the menu item "Downloads":"Data Files". These include fasta files for all available sequences, gff files with complete gene information, and other formats.
<li> Download files with results generated by running searches. From a result page (after running a search) a user can access the "Download Results" link, to a new page where a few different download formats are offered. The file for download includes all IDs in the result. The user selects a format and, in some formats, the user may request additional information about each ID in the result: single valued attributes (e.g., exon count for a geneID) and multi-valued tables (e.g., set of EC numbers for a geneID).
<li> Download fasta files from the Sequence Retrieval Tool,  under the menu item "Tools":"Sequence Retrieval".
<li> Download files that have been uploaded by the community in our websites, available under "Downloads" or "Community".
<li> Downloadable EuPathDB publications, under the menu item "Downloads".

</ul>
</div>
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Acknowledgements</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">acks</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

EuPathDB wishes to acknowledge:<br><br>
<ul class="cirbulletlist">
<li>All the community members who have contributed data (often pre-publication), entered user comments or sent us their suggestions.</li>

<br>
<li>Scientists who provided images to be used as a template for the logos in our websites. These are:
<br><br>
<ul  class="cirbulletlist">
<li> AmoebaDB:  Dr. Graham Clark (London School of Hygiene & Tropical Medicine), Dr. Fiona Henriquez (University of West Scotland), Dr. William Petri (University of Virginia), Dr. Craig Roberts (University of Strathclyde)</li>
<li> GiardiaDB: Dr. Fran Gillin, Dr. Tineke Lauwaet and Dr. Barbara Davids (University of California, San Diego)</li>
<li> MicrosporidiaDB: Dr. Louis Weiss (Albert Einstein School of Medicine)</li>
<li> PiroplasmaDB: Dr. Ellen Yeh (Stanford) for proposing the logo idea. Dr. Lowell Kappemeyer, Dr. Audrey Lau (University of Washington) and Dr. Dirk Dobbelaere (University of Bern) for supplying images.</li>
<li> PlasmoDB: Dr. Pedro Moura for providing images of Giemsa stained parasites</li>
<li> ToxoDB: Dr. Boris Striepen (University of Georgia)</li>
<li> TrichDB: Antonio Pereira-Neves and Marlene Benchimol, Santa Ursula University, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</li>
<li> TriTrypDB: Dr. Rick Tarleton (University of Georgia)</li>
</ul>
</li>

<br>
<li>The team behind EuPathDB:
<ul  class="cirbulletlist">
<br>
<li>Current members: <br>Cristina Aurrecoechea<sup>1</sup>,  Ana Barreto<sup>2,4</sup>, John Brestelli<sup>2,4</sup>, Brian Brunk<sup>2,7</sup>, Shon Cade<sup>2,4</sup>, Ryan Doherty<sup>2,4</sup>, Dave Falke<sup>1</sup>, Steve Fischer<sup>2,4</sup>, Bindu Gajria<sup>2,7</sup>, Xin Gao<sup>2,7</sup>, Alan Gingle<sup>3</sup>, Greg Grant<sup>2,4</sup>, Omar S. Harb<sup>2,7</sup>, Mark Heiges<sup>1</sup>, Sufen Hu<sup>2,7</sup>, John Iodice<sup>2,4</sup>, Jessica C. Kissinger<sup>1,5,8</sup>, Eileen T. Kraemer<sup>6</sup>, Wei Li <sup>2,7</sup>, Deborah F. Pinney<sup>2,4</sup>, David S. Roos<sup>7</sup>, Ganesh Srinivasamoorthy<sup>1</sup>, Christian J. Stoeckert Jr.<sup>2,4</sup>, Haiming Wang<sup>1</sup>, Susanne Warrenfeltz<sup>1</sup>, Betsy Wenthe<sup>1</sup>, Mariann Winkelman<sup>7</sup>.</li>

<br>
<li>Former members: <br>Kathy Couch<sup>1</sup>, Jennifer Dommer<sup>2,4</sup>, Frank Innamorato<sup>2,4</sup>, John A. Miller<sup>6</sup>, Vishal Nayak<sup>2,4</sup>, Cary Pennington<sup>1</sup>, Brian Pitts<sup>1</sup>, Chris Ross<sup>1</sup>, Ryan Thibodeau<sup>1</sup>, Charles Treatman<sup>2,7</sup>, Patricia L. Whetzel<sup>2,4</sup></li>
</ul>
</li>

<br>
<ul>
<li>1 Center for Tropical & Emerging Global Diseases, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602 USA
<li>2 Penn Center for Bioinformatics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA 19104 USA
<li>3 Center for Applied Genetic Technologies, University of Georgia, Athens, GA, 30602 USA
<li>4 Department of Genetics, University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine, Philadelphia, PA 19104 USA
<li>5 Department of Genetics, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602 USA
<li>6 Department of Computer Science, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602 USA
<li>7 Department of Biology, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA 19104 USA
<li>8 Institute of Bioinformatics, University of Georgia, Athens 30602 USA
</ul>

</ul>

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

 

</xmlAnswer>
