<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE xml [
<!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"> 
<!ENTITY lt   "&#60;"> 
<!ENTITY gt   "&#62;">
<!ENTITY sl   "&#47;">
]>

<xmlAnswer>

<!--
<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2010 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag"></attribute>
    <attribute name="authors"></attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
      <![CDATA[
      ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
      <![CDATA[
      ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
      <![CDATA[
      ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid"></attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
      <![CDATA[
      ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>
-->
<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">23 March 2015 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:25388105</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
Harb OS, Roos DS.
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
The Eukaryotic Pathogen Databases: a functional genomic resource integrating data
from human and veterinary parasites.
         ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
          Methods Mol Biol. 2015;1201:1-18.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://link.springer.com/protocol/10.1007%2F978-1-4939-1438-8_1">Full text</a>]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">25388105</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
Over the past 20 years, advances in high-throughput biological techniques and the
availability of computational resources including fast Internet access have
resulted in an explosion of large genome-scale data sets "big data." While such
data are readily available for download and personal use and analysis from a
variety of repositories, often such analysis requires access to seldom-available 
computational skills. As a result a number of databases have emerged to provide
scientists with online tools enabling the interrogation of data without the need 
for sophisticated computational skills beyond basic knowledge of Internet browser
utility. This chapter focuses on the Eukaryotic Pathogen Databases (EuPathDB:
http://eupathdb.org) Bioinformatic Resource Center (BRC) and illustrates some of 
the available tools and methods.
 ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>
<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">23 March 2015 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:24936976</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
Dugan VG, Emrich SJ, Giraldo-Calderón GI, Harb OS, Newman RM,
Pickett BE, Schriml LM, Stockwell TB, Stoeckert CJ Jr, Sullivan
DE, Singh I, Ward DV, Yao A, Zheng J, Barrett T, Birren B,
Brinkac L, Bruno VM, Caler E, Chapman S, Collins FH, Cuomo CA, 
Di Francesco V, Durkin S, Eppinger M, Feldgarden M, Fraser C,
Fricke WF, Giovanni M, Henn MR, Hine E, Hotopp JD, Karsch-Mizrachi
I, Kissinger JC, Lee EM, Mathur P, Mongodin EF, Murphy CI,
Myers G, Neafsey DE, Nelson KE, Nierman WC, Puzak J, Rasko D, 
Roos DS, Sadzewicz L, Silva JC, Sobral B, Squires RB, Stevens
RL, Tallon L, Tettelin H, Wentworth D, White O, Will R,
Wortman J, Zhang Y, Scheuermann RH.
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
Standardized metadata for human pathogen/vector genomic sequences.
         ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
          PLoS One. 2014 Jun 17;9(6):e99979.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0099979">Full text</a> | <a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/fetchObject.action?uri=info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0099979&representation=PDF">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">24936976</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
High throughput sequencing has accelerated the determination of genome sequences 
for thousands of human infectious disease pathogens and dozens of their vectors. 
The scale and scope of these data are enabling genotype-phenotype association
studies to identify genetic determinants of pathogen virulence and
drug/insecticide resistance, and phylogenetic studies to track the origin and
spread of disease outbreaks. To maximize the utility of genomic sequences for
these purposes, it is essential that metadata about the pathogen/vector isolate
characteristics be collected and made available in organized, clear, and
consistent formats. Here we report the development of the GSCID/BRC Project and
Sample Application Standard, developed by representatives of the Genome
Sequencing Centers for Infectious Diseases (GSCIDs), the Bioinformatics Resource 
Centers (BRCs) for Infectious Diseases, and the U.S. National Institute of
Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID), part of the National Institutes of
Health (NIH), informed by interactions with numerous collaborating scientists. It
includes mapping to terms from other data standards initiatives, including the
Genomic Standards Consortium's minimal information (MIxS) and NCBI's
BioSample/BioProjects checklists and the Ontology for Biomedical Investigations
(OBI). The standard includes data fields about characteristics of the organism or
environmental source of the specimen, spatial-temporal information about the
specimen isolation event, phenotypic characteristics of the pathogen/vector
isolated, and project leadership and support. By modeling metadata fields into an
ontology-based semantic framework and reusing existing ontologies and minimum
information checklists, the application standard can be extended to support
additional project-specific data fields and integrated with other data
represented with comparable standards. The use of this metadata standard by all
ongoing and future GSCID sequencing projects will provide a consistent
representation of these data in the BRC resources and other repositories that
leverage these data, allowing investigators to identify relevant genomic
sequences and perform comparative genomics analyses that are both statistically
meaningful and biologically relevant.
 ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>
<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">23 March 2015 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:23175615</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
Aurrecoechea C, Barreto A, Brestelli J, Brunk BP, Cade S, Doherty R, Fischer
S, Gajria B, Gao X, Gingle A, Grant G, Harb OS, Heiges M, Hu S, Iodice J,
Kissinger JC, Kraemer ET, Li W, Pinney DF, Pitts B, Roos DS, Srinivasamoorthy G, 
Stoeckert CJ Jr, Wang H, Warrenfeltz S.
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
EuPathDB: the eukaryotic pathogen database.
         ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
          Nucleic Acids Res. 2013 Jan;41(Database issue):D684-91.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/41/D1/D684.long">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/41/D1/D684.full.pdf+html">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">23175615</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
EuPathDB (http://eupathdb.org) resources include 11 databases supporting
eukaryotic pathogen genomic and functional genomic data, isolate data and
phylogenomics. EuPathDB resources are built using the same infrastructure and
provide a sophisticated search strategy system enabling complex interrogations of
underlying data. Recent advances in EuPathDB resources include the design and
implementation of a new data loading workflow, a new database supporting
Piroplasmida (i.e. Babesia and Theileria), the addition of large amounts of new
data and data types and the incorporation of new analysis tools. New data include
genome sequences and annotation, strand-specific RNA-seq data, splice junction
predictions (based on RNA-seq), phosphoproteomic data, high-throughput
phenotyping data, single nucleotide polymorphism data based on high-throughput
sequencing (HTS) and expression quantitative trait loci data. New analysis tools 
enable users to search for DNA motifs and define genes based on their genomic
colocation, view results from searches graphically (i.e. genes mapped to
chromosomes or isolates displayed on a map) and analyze data from columns in
result tables (word cloud and histogram summaries of column content). The
manuscript herein describes updates to EuPathDB since the previous report
published in NAR in 2010.
 ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">1 May 2012 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:111</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
Stajich JE, Harris T, Brunk BP, Brestelli J, Fischer S, Harb OS, Kissinger JC, Li W, Nayak V, Pinney DF, Stoeckert CJ Jr, Roos DS.
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
FungiDB: an integrated functional genomics database for fungi.  
         ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
          Nucleic Acids Res. 2012 Jan;40(Database issue):D675-81.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/40/D1/D675.abstract">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/40/D1/D675.full">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/40/D1/D675.full.pdf+html">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid"></attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
FungiDB (http://FungiDB.org) is a functional genomic resource for pan-fungal genomes that was developed in partnership with the Eukaryotic Pathogen Bioinformatic resource center (http://EuPathDB.org). FungiDB uses the same infrastructure and user interface as EuPathDB, which allows for sophisticated and integrated searches to be performed using an intuitive graphical system. The current release of FungiDB contains genome sequence and annotation from 18 species spanning several fungal classes, including the Ascomycota classes, Eurotiomycetes, Sordariomycetes, Saccharomycetes and the Basidiomycota orders, Pucciniomycetes and Tremellomycetes, and the basal ‘Zygomycete’ lineage Mucormycotina. Additionally, FungiDB contains cell cycle microarray data, hyphal growth RNA-sequence data and yeast two hybrid interaction data. The underlying genomic sequence and annotation combined with functional data, additional data from the FungiDB standard analysis pipeline and the ability to leverage orthology provides a powerful resource for in silico experimentation. 
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">1 May 2012 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:21901743</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
Fischer S, Brunk BP, Chen F, Gao X, Harb OS, Iodice JB, Shanmugam D, Roos DS, Stoeckert CJ Jr.  
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
Using OrthoMCL to assign proteins to OrthoMCL-DB groups or to cluster proteomes into new ortholog groups.  
         ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
          Curr. Protoc. Bioinform. 35:6.12.1-6.12.19. © 2011 by John Wiley & Sons, Inc. PMID: 21901743. 
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/0471250953.bi0612s35/abstract">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/0471250953.bi0612s35/full">Full text</a> | <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/0471250953.bi0612s35/pdf">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">21901743</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
OrthoMCL is an algorithm for grouping proteins into ortholog groups based on their sequence similarity. OrthoMCL-DB is a public database that allows users to browse and view ortholog groups that were pre-computed using the OrthoMCL algorithm. Version 4 of this database contained 116,536 ortholog groups clustered from 1,270,853 proteins obtained from 88 eukaryotic genomes, 16 archaean genomes, and 34 bacterial genomes. Future versions of OrthoMCL-DB will include more proteomes as more genomes are sequenced. Here, we describe how you can group your proteins of interest into ortholog clusters using two different means provided by the OrthoMCL system. The OrthoMCL-DB Web site has a tool for uploading and grouping a set of protein sequences, typically representing a proteome. This method maps the uploaded proteins to existing groups in OrthoMCL-DB. Alternatively, if you have proteins from a set of genomes that need to be grouped, you can download, install, and run the stand-alone OrthoMCL software. 
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">1 May 2012 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:222</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
Aurrecoechea C., Barreto A, Brestelli J., Brunk BP., Caler EV., Fischer S., Gajria B., Gao X., Gingle A, Grant G., Harb OH., Heiges M., Iodice J., Kissinger JC., Kraemer ET., Li W., Nayak V., Pennington C., Pinney DF., Pitts B., Roos DS., Srinivasamoorthy G., Stoeckert CJ Jr., Treatman C., and Wang H. 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
AmoebaDB and MicrosporidiaDB: functional genomic resources for Amoebozoa and Microsporidia species. 
         ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
          Nucleic Acids Research. 39(Database issue):D612-9, 2011 Jan.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/39/suppl_1/D612.abstract">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/39/suppl_1/D612.full">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/39/suppl_1/D612.full.pdf+html">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid"></attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
AmoebaDB (http://AmoebaDB.org) and MicrosporidiaDB (http://MicrosporidiaDB.org) are new functional genomic databases serving the amoebozoa and microsporidia research communities, respectively. AmoebaDB contains the genomes of three Entamoeba species (E. dispar, E. invadens and E. histolityca) and microarray expression data for E. histolytica. MicrosporidiaDB contains the genomes of Encephalitozoon cuniculi, E. intestinalis and E. bieneusi. The databases belong to the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) funded EuPathDB (http://EuPathDB.org) Bioinformatics Resource Center family of integrated databases and assume the same architectural and graphical design as other EuPathDB resources such as PlasmoDB and TriTrypDB. Importantly they utilize the graphical strategy builder that affords a database user the ability to ask complex multi-data-type questions with relative ease and versatility. Genomic scale data can be queried based on BLAST searches, annotation keywords and gene ID searches, GO terms, sequence motifs, protein characteristics, phylogenetic relationships and functional data such as transcript (microarray and EST evidence) and protein expression data. Search strategies can be saved within a user’s profile for future retrieval and may also be shared with other researchers using a unique strategy web address. 
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>



<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">1 May 2012 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:21705364</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
Fischer S, Aurrecoechea C, Brunk BP, Gao X, Harb OS, Kraemer ET, Pennington C, Treatman C, Kissinger JC, Roos DS, Stoeckert CJ.  
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
The Strategies WDK: a graphical search interface and web development kit for functional genomics databases.  
         ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
         Database (Oxford). 2011 Jun 23;2011:bar027. Print 2011.  PMID: 21705364 PMCID: PMC3122067 
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://database.oxfordjournals.org/content/2011/bar027.abstract">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://database.oxfordjournals.org/content/2011/bar027.full">Full text</a> | <a href="http://database.oxfordjournals.org/content/2011/bar027.full.pdf+html">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">21705364</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
Web sites associated with the Eukaryotic Pathogen Bioinformatics Resource Center (EuPathDB.org) have recently introduced a graphical user interface, the Strategies WDK, intended to make advanced searching and set and interval operations easy and accessible to all users. With a design guided by usability studies, the system helps motivate researchers to perform dynamic computational experiments and explore relationships across data sets. For example, PlasmoDB users seeking novel therapeutic targets may wish to locate putative enzymes that distinguish pathogens from their hosts, and that are expressed during appropriate developmental stages. When a researcher runs one of the approximately 100 searches available on the site, the search is presented as a first step in a strategy. The strategy is extended by running additional searches, which are combined with set operators (union, intersect or minus), or genomic interval operators (overlap, contains). A graphical display uses Venn diagrams to make the strategy’s flow obvious. The interface facilitates interactive adjustment of the component searches with changes propagating forward through the strategy. Users may save their strategies, creating protocols that can be shared with colleagues. The strategy system has now been deployed on all EuPathDB databases, and successfully deployed by other projects. The Strategies WDK uses a configurable MVC architecture that is compatible with most genomics and biological warehouse databases, and is available for download at code.google.com/p/strategies-wdk. 
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">1 May 2012 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:333</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
H. Wang, J. DeBarry, J. C. Kissinger 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
SynView - Synteny Browser with GBrowse Integration
         ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
           <a href="http://www.iconceptpress.com/01/site/publication.viewPapers.php?publicationID=BK002A">A Practical Guide to Bioinformatics Analysis- 2010 iConcept Press Ltd.</a>
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://www.iconceptpress.com/01/site/publication.downloadPaper.php?paperID=100917052357">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid"></attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
Over the last decade, the field of comparative genomics has evolved from its infancy and has arguably be- come a cornerstone of biological investigation. Traditionally, comparative efforts were focused on individual groups of evolutionarily related genes shared between species (orthologs), or on genes involved in specific biological pathways. These comparisons have been inestimably useful in increasing the understanding of the biology of model organisms, and providing insight into the evolution of discreet biological phenomena. The advent of whole-genome sequencing has expanded comparative investigations to include the routine comparison of entire genomes. Such comparisons have facilitated examination of the pattern and tempo of genome evolution across the tree of life. Genome comparisons can be used to facilitate traditional compara- tive investigations, aid in the annotation of newly sequenced genomes, and provide the framework for larger questions about the processes governing genome evolution.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">1 May 2012 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:444</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
Aurrecoechea C. Brestelli J. Brunk BP. Fischer S. Gajria B. Gao X. Gingle A. Grant G. Harb OS. Heiges M. Innamorato F. Iodice J. Kissinger JC. Kraemer ET. Li W. Miller JA. Nayak V. Pennington C. Pinney DF. Roos DS. Ross C. Srinivasamoorthy G. Stoeckert CJ Jr. Thibodeau R. Treatman C. Wang H. 
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
EuPathDB: a portal to eukaryotic pathogen databases
         ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
          Nucleic Acids Research 2010 38(Database issue):D415-9
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/38/suppl_1/D415.abstract">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/38/suppl_1/D415.full">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/38/suppl_1/D415.full.pdf+html">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid"></attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
EuPathDB (http://EuPathDB.org; formerly ApiDB) is an integrated database covering the eukaryotic pathogens of the genera Cryptosporidium, Giardia, Leishmania, Neospora, Plasmodium, Toxoplasma, Trichomonas and Trypanosoma. While each of these groups is supported by a taxon-specific database built upon the same infrastructure, the EuPathDB portal offers an entry point to all these resources, and the opportunity to leverage orthology for searches across genera. The most recent release of EuPathDB includes updates and changes affecting data content, infrastructure and the user interface, improving data access and enhancing the user experience. EuPathDB currently supports more than 80 searches and the recently-implemented ‘search strategy’ system enables users to construct complex multi-step searches via a graphical interface. Search results are dynamically displayed as the strategy is constructed or modified, and can be downloaded, saved, revised, or shared with other database users. 
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>



<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2010 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:19843604</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Aslett M, Aurrecoechea C, Berriman M, Brestelli J, Brunk BP, Carrington M, 
        Depledge DP, Fischer S, Gajria B, Gao X, Gardner MJ, Gingle A, Grant G, 
        Harb OS, Heiges M, Hertz-Fowler C, Houston R, Innamorato F, Iodice J, 
        Kissinger JC, Kraemer E, Li W, Logan FJ, Miller JA, Mitra S, Myler PJ, 
        Nayak V, Pennington C, Phan I, Pinney DF, Ramasamy G, Rogers MB, Roos DS, 
        Ross C, Sivam D, Smith DF, Srinivasamoorthy G, Stoeckert CJ Jr., 
        Subramanian S, Thibodeau R, Tivey A, Treatman C, Velarde G, Wang H.
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
         TriTrypDB: a functional genomic resource for the Trypanosomatidae
         ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
          Nucleic Acids Research 2010 38(Database issue):D457-D462; doi:10.1093/nar/gkp851
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/gkp851">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/38/suppl_1/D457">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/38/suppl_1/D457">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">19843604</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
TriTrypDB (http://tritrypdb.org) is an integrated database
providing access to genome-scale datasets for kinetoplastid
parasites, and supporting a variety of complex queries
driven by research and development needs. TriTrypDB is a
collaborative project, utilizing the GUS/WDK computational
infrastructure developed by the Eukaryotic Pathogen
Bioinformatics Resource Center (EuPathDB.org) to integrate
genome annotation and analyses from GeneDB and elsewhere
with a wide variety of functional genomics datasets made
available by members of the global research community, often
pre-publication. Currently, TriTrypDB integrates datasets
from Leishmania braziliensis, L. infantum, L. major, L.
tarentolae, Trypanosoma brucei and T. cruzi. Users may
examine individual genes or chromosomal spans in their
genomic context, including syntenic alignments with other
kinetoplastid organisms. Data within TriTrypDB can be
interrogated utilizing a sophisticated search strategy
system that enables a user to construct complex queries
combining multiple data types. All search strategies are
stored, allowing future access and integrated searches.
'User Comments' may be added to any gene page, enhancing
available annotation; such comments become immediately
searchable via the text search, and are forwarded to
curators for incorporation into the reference annotation
when appropriate.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>


<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2009 16:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:18957442</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
         Aurrecoechea, C., J. Brestelli, B. P. Brunk, J. Dommer, S. Fischer, 
         B. Gajria, X. Gao, A. Gingle, G. Grant, O. S. Harb, M. Heiges, F. Innamorato, 
         J. Iodice, J. C. Kissinger, E. Kraemer, W. Li, J. A. Miller, V. Nayak, 
         C. Pennington, D. F. Pinney, D. S. Roos, C. Ross, C. J. Stoeckert, Jr., 
         C. Treatman, and H. Wang
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        PlasmoDB: a functional genomic database for malaria parasites
        ]]>
     </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
           Nucleic Acids Res. 2009. 37:D539-D543
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
         [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/gkn814">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/gkn814">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/gkn814">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">18957442</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
PlasmoDB (http://PlasmoDB.org) is a functional genomic
database for Plasmodium spp. that provides a resource for
data analysis and visualization in a gene-by-gene or
genome-wide scale. PlasmoDB belongs to a family of genomic
resources that are housed under the EuPathDB
(http://EuPathDB.org) Bioinformatics Resource Center (BRC)
umbrella. The latest release, PlasmoDB 5.5, contains
numerous new data types from several broad
categories--annotated genomes, evidence of transcription,
proteomics evidence, protein function evidence, population
biology and evolution. Data in PlasmoDB can be queried by
selecting the data of interest from a query grid or drop
down menus. Various results can then be combined with each
other on the query history page. Search results can be
downloaded with associated functional data and registered
users can store their query history for future retrieval or
analysis.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>


<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2009 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:18824479</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
         Aurrecoechea, C., J. Brestelli, B. P. Brunk, J. M. Carlton, J. Dommer, 
         S. Fischer, B. Gajria, X. Gao, A. Gingle, G. Grant, O. S. Harb, M. Heiges, 
         F. Innamorato, J. Iodice, J. C. Kissinger, E. Kraemer, W. Li, J. A. Miller, 
         H. G. Morrison, V. Nayak, C. Pennington, D. F. Pinney, D. S. Roos, 
         C. Ross, C. J. Stoeckert, Jr., S. Sullivan, C. Treatman, and H. Wang
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        GiardiaDB and TrichDB: integrated genomic resources for the eukaryotic protist pathogens Giardia lamblia and Trichomonas vaginalis
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
        Nucleic Acids Res. 2009. 37:D526-D530
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/gkn631">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/gkn631">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/gkn631">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">18824479</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
GiardiaDB (http://GiardiaDB.org) and TrichDB
(http://TrichDB.org) house the genome databases for Giardia
lamblia and Trichomonas vaginalis, respectively, and
represent the latest additions to the EuPathDB
(http://EuPathDB.org) family of functional genomic
databases. GiardiaDB and TrichDB employ the same framework
as other EuPathDB sites (CryptoDB, PlasmoDB and ToxoDB),
supporting fully integrated and searchable databases.
Genomic-scale data available via these resources may be
queried based on BLAST searches, annotation keywords and
gene ID searches, GO terms, sequence motifs and other
protein characteristics. Functional queries may also be
formulated, based on transcript and protein expression data
from a variety of platforms. Phylogenetic relationships may
also be interrogated. The ability to combine the results
from independent queries, and to store queries and query
results for future use facilitates complex, genome-wide
mining of functional genomic data.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>


<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2007 16:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:18003657</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        B. Gajria, A. Bahl, J. Brestelli, J. Dommer, S. Fischer, 
        X. Gao, M. Heiges, J. Iodice, J. C. Kissinger, A. J. Mackey, et al.
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        ToxoDB: an integrated Toxoplasma gondii database resource
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[    
        Nucleic Acids Res. 2007. 36:D553-6
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/gkm981v1">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/gkm981v1">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/gkm981v1">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">18003657</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
ToxoDB (http://ToxoDB.org) is a genome and functional
genomic database for the protozoan parasite Toxoplasma
gondii. It incorporates the sequence and annotation of the
T. gondii ME49 strain, as well as genome sequences for the
GT1, VEG and RH (Chr Ia, Chr Ib) strains. Sequence
information is integrated with various other genomic-scale
data, including community annotation, ESTs, gene expression
and proteomics data. ToxoDB has matured significantly since
its initial release. Here we outline the numerous updates
with respect to the data and increased functionality
available on the website.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2007 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:17098930</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Cristina Aurrecoechea, Mark Heiges, Haiming Wang, Zhiming Wang, 
        Steve Fischer, Philippa Rhodes, John Miller, Eileen Kraemer, 
        Christian J. Stoeckert, Jr., David S. Roos and Jessica C. Kissinger
    </attribute>
    
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        ApiDB: integrated resources for the apicomplexan bioinformatics resource center
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
        Nucleic Acids Research. 2007. 35:D427-30
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/gkl880?ijkey=7QHavFAOdzzOSLM&keytype=ref">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/gkl880?ijkey=7QHavFAOdzzOSLM&keytype=ref">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/gkl880?ijkey=7QHavFAOdzzOSLM&keytype=ref">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">17098930</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
ApiDB (http://ApiDB.org) represents a unified entry point
for the NIH-funded Apicomplexan Bioinformatics Resource
Center (BRC) that integrates numerous database resources and
multiple data types. The phylum Apicomplexa comprises
numerous veterinary and medically important parasitic
protozoa including human pathogenic species of the genera
Cryptosporidium, Plasmodium and Toxoplasma. ApiDB serves not
only as a database in its own right, but as a single
web-based point of entry that unifies access to three major
existing individual organism databases (PlasmoDB.org,
ToxoDB.org and CryptoDB.org), and integrates these databases
with data available from additional sources. Through the
ApiDB site, users may pose queries and search all available
apicomplexan data and tools, or they may visit individual
component organism databases.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2006 20:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:17029963</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Christian J. Stoeckert Jr., Steve Fisher, Jessica Kissinger, 
        Mark Heiges, Cristina Aurrecoechea, Bindu Gajria, David S. Roos
    </attribute>      
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        PlasmoDB v5: New Looks, New Genomes
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
        Trends in Parasitology. 2006. 22(12): 543-546
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?db=pubmed&cmd=Retrieve&dopt=AbstractPlus&list_uids=17029963&query_hl=1&itool=pubmed_docsum">Abstract</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">17029963</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
Version 5.1 of PlasmoDB, a resource for malaria parasite
genomic and functional genomics datasets, was released in
August 2006. This new release includes additional Plasmodium
genomes and a newly designed website. The new site reflects
the status of PlasmoDB as a member of a linked family of
Apicomplexan databases.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>


<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2006 19:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">ISBN:1-59454-995-8</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Patricia L. Whetzel, Shailesh V. Date, Kobby Essien, Martin J. Fraunholz, 
        Bindu Gajria, Gregory R. Grant, John Iodice, Jessica C. Kissinger, 
        Philip T. Labo, Arthur J. Milgram, David S. Roos, and Christian J. Stoeckert Jr.
    </attribute>        
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        PlasmoDB: The Plasmodium Genomics and Functional Genomics Resource
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
        In silico Genomics and Proteomics: Functional Annotation of Genomes and Proteins. Nicola Mulder and Rolf Apweiler (eds.). Nova Science Publishers. 2006
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links"/>
    <attribute name="pmid"></attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn">1-59454-995-8</attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>


<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2006 18:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:16844709</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Haiming Wang, Yanqi Su, Aaron J. Mackey, Eileen T. Kraemer and Jessica C. Kissinger
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        SynView: A GBrowse-compatible Approach to Visualizing Comparative Genome Data
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
        Bioinformatics. 2006. 22(18):2308-2309
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://bioinformatics.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/short/22/18/2308">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://bioinformatics.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/22/18/2308">Full text</a> |<a href="http://bioinformatics.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/22/18/2308">PDF</a> | <a href="http://eupathdb.org/apps/SynView/">Supplement</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">16844709</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
SUMMARY: We present SynView, a simple and generic approach
to dynamically visualize multi-species comparative genome
data. It is a light-weight application based on the popular
and configurable web-based GBrowse framework. It can be used
with a variety of databases and provides the user with a
high degree of interactivity. The tool is written in Perl
and runs on top of the GBrowse framework. It is in use in
the PlasmoDB (http://www.PlasmoDB.org) and the CryptoDB
(http://www.CryptoDB.org) projects and can be easily
integrated into other cross-species comparative genome
projects. AVAILABILITY: The program and instructions are
freely available at http://www.ApiDB.org/apps/SynView/
CONTACT: jkissing@uga.edu.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>


<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2006 17:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:16381902</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Heiges M, Wang H, Robinson E, Aurrecoechea C, Gao X, Kaluskar N, 
        Rhodes P, Wang S, He CZ, Su Y, Miller J, Kraemer E, Kissinger JC.
    </attribute>
    
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        CryptoDB: a <i>Cryptosporidium</i> bioinformatics resource update
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
        Nucleic Acids Res. 2006 Jan 1;34:D419-22
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/34/suppl_1/D419">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/34/suppl_1/D419">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/34/suppl_1/D419">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">16381902</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
The database, CryptoDB (http://CryptoDB.org), is a community
bioinformatics resource for the AIDS-related
apicomplexan-parasite, Cryptosporidium. CryptoDB integrates
whole genome sequence and annotation with expressed sequence
tag and genome survey sequence data and provides
supplemental bioinformatics analyses and data-mining tools.
A simple, yet comprehensive web interface is available for
mining and visualizing the data. CryptoDB is allied with the
databases PlasmoDB and ToxoDB via ApiDB, an
NIH/NIAID-fundedBioinformatics Resource Center. Recent
updates to CryptoDB include the deposition of annotated
genome sequences for Cryptosporidium parvum and
Cryptosporidium hominis, migration to a relational database
(GUS), a new query and visualization interface and the
introduction of Web services.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2006 16:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:16381887</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Feng Chen, Aaron J. Mackey, Christian J. Stoeckert Jr. and David S. Roos
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        OrthoMCL-DB: querying a comprehensive multi-species collection of ortholog groups
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
        Nucleic Acids Res. 2006 Jan 1;34:D363-8        
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/34/suppl_1/D363">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/34/suppl_1/D363">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/34/suppl_1/D363">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">16381887</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
The OrthoMCL database (http://orthomcl.cbil.upenn.edu)
houses ortholog group predictions for 55 species, including
16 bacterial and 4 archaeal genomes representing
phylogenetically diverse lineages, and most currently
available complete eukaryotic genomes: 24 unikonts (12
animals, 9 fungi, microsporidium, Dictyostelium, Entamoeba),
4 plants/algae and 7 apicomplexan parasites. OrthoMCL
software was used to cluster proteins based on sequence
similarity, using an all-against-all BLAST search of each
species' proteome, followed by normalization of
inter-species differences, and Markov clustering. A total of
511,797 proteins (81.6% of the total dataset) were clustered
into 70,388 ortholog groups. The ortholog database may be
queried based on protein or group accession numbers, keyword
descriptions or BLAST similarity. Ortholog groups exhibiting
specific phyletic patterns may also be identified, using
either a graphical interface or a text-based Phyletic
Pattern Expression grammar. Information for ortholog groups
includes the phyletic profile, the list of member proteins
and a multiple sequence alignment, a statistical summary and
graphical view of similarities, and a graphical
representation of domain architecture. OrthoMCL software,
the entire FASTA dataset employed and clustering results are
available for download. OrthoMCL-DB provides a centralized
warehouse for orthology prediction among multiple species,
and will be updated and expanded as additional genome
sequence data become available.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2006 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:16311071</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Duraisingh M, Ferdig MT, Stoeckert CJ, Volkman SK, McGovern VP
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        <i>Plasmodium</i> research in the postgenomic era
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[            
        Trends Parasitol. 2006 22(1):1-4
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science?_ob=ArticleURL&amp;_udi=B6W7G-4HNSB6D-2&amp;_coverDate=01%2F31%2F2006&amp;_alid=373299208&amp;_rdoc=1&amp;_fmt=&amp;_orig=search&amp;_qd=1&amp;_cdi=6626&amp;_sort=d&amp;view=c&amp;_acct=C000050221&amp;_version=1&amp;_urlVersion=0&amp;_userid=10&amp;md5=b4b05abd69cfeb5ef1e66ca91cce994b">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science?_ob=ArticleURL&amp;_udi=B6W7G-4HNSB6D-2&amp;_user=10&amp;_coverDate=01%2F31%2F2006&amp;_alid=373299208&amp;_rdoc=1&amp;_fmt=full&amp;_orig=search&amp;_qd=1&amp;_cdi=6626&amp;_sort=d&amp;_docanchor=&amp;view=c&amp;_acct=C000050221&amp;_version=1&amp;_urlVersion=0&amp;_userid=10&amp;md5=83f0b10de2980b3fef183d3e7268b9b2">Full text</a> | <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science?_ob=MImg&amp;_imagekey=B6W7G-4HNSB6D-2-1&amp;_cdi=6626&amp;_user=10&amp;_orig=search&amp;_coverDate=01%2F31%2F2006&amp;_qd=1&amp;_sk=999779998&amp;view=c&amp;wchp=dGLzVlz-zSkzS&amp;md5=3b147441231bcdb654a864bd3256aab9&amp;ie=/sdarticle.pdf">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">16311071</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
The complete genomic sequence of Plasmodium falciparum
strain 3D7 was published in October 2002. At the Next Steps
in Malaria Research meeting in April 2005, the next
practical steps were considered and the priorities ranked
for postgenomic research in Plasmodium. The high-throughput
approaches that will help to answer the major biological
questions regarding Plasmodium should, like the genome
project itself, build community-shared resources, and
efforts must be made to help researchers ready themselves to
use the tools that will become available.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2005 20:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">ISBN:0-9542464-6-2</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        J.C. Kissinger and D.S. Roos
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        Getting the most out of bioinformatics resources
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
        <i>In</i>: Malaria Parasites, A.P. Waters & C.J. Janse, editors.  Horizon, Norfolk UK. 2004
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links"/>
    <attribute name="pmid"></attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn">0-9542464-6-2 </attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2005 19:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:15911631</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Khan, A., S. Taylor, C. Su, A.J. Mackey, J. Boyle, R. Cole, D. Glover, K. Tang, 
        I.T. Paulsen, M. Berriman, J.C. Boothroyd, E.R. Pfefferkorn, J.P. Dubey, J.W. 
        Ajioka, D.S. Roos, J.C. Wootton and L.D. Sibley
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        Composite genome map and recombination parameters derived from three archetypal lineages of <i>Toxoplasma gondii</i>
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
        Nucl. Acids Res. 2005 33:2980-2992
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/33/9/2980">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/33/9/2980">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/33/9/2980">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">15911631</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
Toxoplasma gondii is a highly successful protozoan parasite
in the phylum Apicomplexa, which contains numerous animal
and human pathogens. T.gondii is amenable to cellular,
biochemical, molecular and genetic studies, making it a
model for the biology of this important group of parasites.
To facilitate forward genetic analysis, we have developed a
high-resolution genetic linkage map for T.gondii. The
genetic map was used to assemble the scaffolds from a 10X
shotgun whole genome sequence, thus defining 14 chromosomes
with markers spaced at approximately 300 kb intervals across
the genome. Fourteen chromosomes were identified comprising
a total genetic size of approximately 592 cM and an average
map unit of approximately 104 kb/cM. Analysis of the genetic
parameters in T.gondii revealed a high frequency of closely
adjacent, apparent double crossover events that may
represent gene conversions. In addition, we detected large
regions of genetic homogeneity among the archetypal clonal
lineages, reflecting the relatively few genetic outbreeding
events that have occurred since their recent origin. Despite
these unusual features, linkage analysis proved to be
effective in mapping the loci determining several drug
resistances. The resulting genome map provides a framework
for analysis of complex traits such as virulence and
transmission, and for comparative population genetic
studies.
    ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2005 18:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:15994520</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Roos, D.S.
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        Themes and variations in apicomplexan parasite biology
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[            
        Science. 2005 309:72-73
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/summary/309/5731/72">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/full/309/5731/72">Full text</a> | <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/cgi/reprint/309/5731/72.pdf">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">15994520</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>


<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2005 17:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:16151400</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Chaudhary, K., and D.S. Roos
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        Protozoan genomics for drug discovery
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
        Nature Biotechnol. 2005 23:1089-1091
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://www.nature.com/nbt/journal/v23/n9/abs/nbt0905-1089.html">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://www.nature.com/nbt/journal/v23/n9/full/nbt0905-1089.html">Full text</a> | <a href="http://www.nature.com/nbt/journal/v23/n9/pdf/nbt0905-1089.pdf">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">16151400</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>


<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2005 16:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:16324218</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Radke, J.R., M.S. Behnke, A.J. Mackey, J.B. Radke, D.S. Roos and M.W. White
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        The transcriptome of <i>Toxoplasma gondii</i>
        ]]>
    </attribute> 
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[            
        BMC Bioinformatics 2005:3-26
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://www.biomedcentral.com/1741-7007/3/26/abstract">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://www.biomedcentral.com/1741-7007/3/26">Full text</a> | <a href="http://www.biomedcentral.com/content/pdf/1741-7007-3-26.pdf">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">16324218</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
BACKGROUND: Toxoplasma gondii gives rise to toxoplasmosis,
among the most prevalent parasitic diseases of animals and
man. Transformation of the tachzyoite stage into the latent
bradyzoite-cyst form underlies chronic disease and leads to
a lifetime risk of recrudescence in individuals whose immune
system becomes compromised. Given the importance of tissue
cyst formation, there has been intensive focus on the
development of methods to study bradyzoite differentiation,
although the molecular basis for the developmental switch is
still largely unknown. RESULTS: We have used serial analysis
of gene expression (SAGE) to define the Toxoplasma gondii
transcriptome of the intermediate-host life cycle that leads
to the formation of the bradyzoite/tissue cyst. A broad view
of gene expression is provided by >4-fold coverage from nine
distinct libraries (approximately 300,000 SAGE tags)
representing key developmental transitions in primary
parasite populations and in laboratory strains representing
the three canonical genotypes. SAGE tags, and their
corresponding mRNAs, were analyzed with respect to
abundance, uniqueness, and antisense/sense polarity and
chromosome distribution and developmental specificity.
CONCLUSION: This study demonstrates that phenotypic
transitions during parasite development were marked by
unique stage-specific mRNAs that accounted for 18% of the
total SAGE tags and varied from 1-5% of the tags in each
developmental stage. We have also found that Toxoplasma mRNA
pools have a unique parasite-specific composition with 1 in
5 transcripts encoding Apicomplexa-specific genes
functioning in parasite invasion and transmission.
Developmentally co-regulated genes were dispersed across all
Toxoplasma chromosomes, as were tags representing each
abundance class, and a variety of biochemical pathways
indicating that trans-acting mechanisms likely control gene
expression in this parasite. We observed distinct
similarities in the specificity and expression levels of
mRNAs in primary populations (Day-6 post-sporozoite
infection) that occur prior to the onset of bradyzoite
development that were uniquely shared with the virulent Type
I-RH laboratory strain suggesting that development of RH may
be arrested. By contrast, strains from Type II-Me49B7 and
Type III-VEGmsj contain SAGE tags corresponding to
bradyzoite genes, which suggests that priming of
developmental expression likely plays a role in the greater
capacity of these strains to complete bradyzoite
development.
    ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>

<record>
    <attribute name="record_date">31 March 2005 15:00</attribute>
    <attribute name="tag">PubMed:16008573</attribute>
    <attribute name="authors">
        Stoeckert CJ Jr.
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="title">
        <![CDATA[
        Functional genomics databases on the web
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="reference">
        <![CDATA[
        Cell Microbiol. 2005 7(8), 1053-9
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="links">
        <![CDATA[
        [ <a href="http://www.blackwell-synergy.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1462-5822.2005.00553.x">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://www.blackwell-synergy.com/doi/full/10.1111/j.1462-5822.2005.00553.x">Full text</a> | <a href="http://www.blackwell-synergy.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/j.1462-5822.2005.00553.x">PDF</a> ]
        ]]>
    </attribute>
    <attribute name="pmid">16008573</attribute>
    <attribute name="isbn"></attribute>
    <attribute name="abstract">
        <![CDATA[
Experiments involving high-throughput methods for measuring
transcripts, proteins and metabolites constitute the area of
functional genomics. These experiments are highly context
dependent and require much more detail about the
experimental design, sample and protocols used than in
genomics. Functional genomics databases are needed that
follow established and emerging standards. Functional
genomic databases are not yet very common; however, there
are a few focused on microbial genomes and a couple
integrative systems are available for setting up functional
genomics databases.
        ]]>
    </attribute>
</record>


</xmlAnswer>
