<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xmlAnswer>

   <record>
       <attribute name="term"></attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">3-Frame translation (forward)</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Translation of a nucleotide sequence in all three possible reading frames in one direction, usually forward designates "on the top strand" of DNA
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">3-Frame translation (reverse)</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Translation of a nucleotide sequence in all three possible reading frames in the reverse direction, usually reverse designates "on the bottom strand" of DNA
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">AA sequence</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Amino acid sequence
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Affymetrix genotyped SNP probes</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Probes on Affymetrix SNP (single nucleotide polymorphism) arrays, which are used for SNP genotyping. See URLURLAffymetrix genotyped SNP probesURLURL and URLURLAffymetrix genotyped SNP probesURLURL (see Affymetrix microarray technology) and http://www.affymetrix.com/technology/mrd_technology.affx
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Affymetrix microarray technology</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Array manufacturing technology developed by Affymetrix. Combines semiconductor fabrication techniques, solid phase chemistry, combinatorial chemistry, molecular biology, and robotics to generate a photolithographic manufacturing process in which oligonucleotides are synthesized directly on a chip (http://www.affymetrix.com/technology/manufacturing/index.affx)
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Affymetrix probes</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Probe on an Affymetrix microarray designed to determine whether or not the complementary sequence of RNA or DNA is present in a sample. Generally 25 nucleotides in length (25-mers), their short length provides higher specificity than longer probes. See Affymetrix microarray technology. For more information about Affymetrix probes, see http://www.affymetrix.com/technology/design/index.affx
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Annotation</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Identified feature within a sequence, such as a known or predicted gene, domain, motif, posttranslational modification, etc.
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Annotation density</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Level to which a nucleotide or protein sequence has been annotated. See Annotation
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">ApiCyc</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Database/utility on URLURLApiCycURLURL used for searching and visualizing metabolic pathway information for organisms in ApiDB; derivative database generated by analyzing various genomes (for example from Plasmodium, Cryptosporidium, and Toxoplasma) with SRI International's pathway tools
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">ApiDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">ApiDoTS alignments</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Consensus sequences found in the ApiDotS database and generated by clustering and assembling Apicomplexan mRNA and URLURLApiDoTS alignmentsURLURL sequences. These consensus sequences were subjected to database searches against protein sequences and protein domain sequences
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Apicoplast</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Nonphotosynthetic plastid found in almost all protozoan parasites belonging to the phylum Apicocomplexa that have been examined. The apicoplast is surrounded by four membranes, giving rise to the theory that its presence in the Apicomplexa is the result of a secondary endosymbiosios (acquired by the engulfment of an ancestral alga and retention of the algal plastid). Similar to other endosymbiotic organelles (mitochondria, chloroplasts), the apicoplast contains its own genome as well as proteins that are encoded in the nucleus and post-translationally imported. The apicoplast is a vital organelle to the parasite's long-term survival
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Attributes</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Inherent characteristics or features. In a database, a data item related to a database object. For example, attributes of genes can include features such as introns and untranslated regions (UTRs)
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">BLAST</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Basic local alignment search tool, a sequence similarity search tool used to quickly find local alignments between a query sequence and sequences in nucleotide or protein databases. Different versions of this search tool are available to match the type of query sequence and database used. See blastn, blastp, blastx, tblastn, and tblastx
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Boolean</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
System of logical thought developed by George Boole (1815-1864). In Boolean searching, an "and" operator between two words or values (for example, "apple AND orange") generates a search for items in a database containing both of the words or values. Similarly, an "or" operator between two words or values (for example, "apple OR orange") generates a search for items containing either word
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">CDS</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Coding sequence. Region of nucleotides that corresponds to the sequence of amino acids in a predicted protein and that includes start and stop codons. Unexpressed sequences, including the 5'-UTR, the 3'-UTR, and introns, are not included within a CDS. The CDS usually does not correspond to the actual mRNA sequence
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Centromere</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Region of the chromosome or chromosomal structure essential for division and retention of the chromosome within the cell; the point of a chromosome where the spindle fibers attach to pull the chromosome apart during cell divisionChromosome
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Coil</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
"Three-dimensional spiral structure, in this case a protein macromolecules"
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Contig</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Contiguous genomic sequence assembled from overlapping primary sequences representing overlapping regions of a particular chromosome
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">CryptoCyc</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Database/utility built by analyzing the Cryptosporidium genome with SRI International's pathway tools; used for searching and visualizing Cryptosporidium metabolic pathway information
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">CryptoDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Curated annotation</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Annotations made under the supervision of a curator as opposed to a purely computational prediction. URLURLCurated annotationURLURL Curated prediciton often contain combinations of evidence to support the annotation
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">DNA/GC content</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Content of guanine (G) and cytosine (C) in a fragment of DNA or a genome. Because GC pairs are more thermostable compared to the AT pairs, it was commonly believed that GC content played a vital part in adaptation to high temperatures, a hypothesis that has been refuted. URLURLDNA/GC contentURLURL In the genome browser, the DNA/GC content track displays a GC content graph of the reference sequence at low magnifications and the DNA sequence itself at higher magnifications
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Dalton</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Unit of mass abbreviated Da and used to express atomic and molecular masses
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">EC numbers</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Enzyme Commission numbers. EC numbers constitute the numerical classification scheme for enzymes based on the chemical reactions they catalyze. EC numbers do not refer to the enzymes, but rather to the reactions they catalyze
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">EST</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Expressed sequence tag. Short (typically 100-500 base pairs) partial URLURLESTURLURL produced by single-shot sequencing of a cloned mRNA (cDNA) and often used to identify gene transcripts
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">EST alignments</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Alignments of expressed sequence tags (ESTs) with a corresponding genomic region. For example, in URLURLEST alignmentsURLURL you can visualize URLURLEST alignmentsURLURL alignments by clicking on the ""View this sequence in the genome browser"" link and turning on the URLURLEST alignmentsURLURL Alignments track. Useful for identifying intron boundaries
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">EST clusters</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Groups of homologous, overlapping URLURLEST clustersURLURL sequences created to reduce redundancy of the URLURLEST clustersURLURL database
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Expression level</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Level at which an mRNA or protein is present in a sample. Value can be absolute or relative to other mRNA or protein species in the sample
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Expression profile</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Pattern of expression of one or more genes or proteins over time or a set of experimental conditions, for example during development, drug treatment, or as result of a genetic mutation such as a knockout <font color="red">J said ask Greg</font>
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Expression profile correlation</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Method for correlation of gene expression profiles with gene ontology annotations developed for the purpose of identifying groups of genes, pathways, and processes concertedly reacting to experimental perturbations"
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Expression timing</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Timing of gene expression during a developmental, metabolic, regulatory, or other biological process or response
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GBrowse</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Interactive genome browser developed by the Generic Model Organism Database (GMOD) project (http://www.gmod.org) that can be customized to show selected chromosomal features as well as display user-provided annotations
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GBrowse track</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
In the URLURLGBrowse trackURLURL viewer, a line of data that corresponds to a particular type of genomic information or feature and distinguished by a particular shape or color
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GLEAN gene</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Predicted gene sequence generated by GLEAN, an algorithm that integrates different sources of gene structure evidence (for example, gene model predictions, EST/protein genomic sequence alignments, and SAGE/peptide tags) to produce a consensus gene prediction in the absence of known genes
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GO</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Gene Ontology project. Collaborative project that has developed three structured controlled vocabularies (ontologies) to describe gene products in terms of their associated biological processes, cellular components, and molecular functions in a species-independent manner. The use of a consistent vocabulary allows genes from different species to be compared based on their GO annotations
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GO component</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Gene Ontology term used to describe a cellular component, the locations where a gene product may act, rather than physical features of proteins or RNAs. For example, membrane (GO:0016020), extrinsic to membrane (GO:0019898), and integral to membrane (GO:0016021). See GO
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GO function</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Gene Ontology term used to describe the molecular function of a gene product, the jobs that it does or the "abilities" that it has (for example, transporting compounds, binding to things, holding things together, and changing one thing into another. This is different from the biological processes the gene product is involved in, which involve more than one activity. See GO
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GO process</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Gene Ontology term used to describe a biological process associated with the gene product, a recognized series of events or molecular functions. A biological process is not equivalent to a pathway, though some URLURLGO processURLURL terms do describe pathways. See GO
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GO term</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Gene Ontology term. The building blocks of the URLURLGO termURLURL Ontology, each term is assigned to one of the three ontologies: molecular function, cellular component, or biological process. Each URLURLGO termURLURL term consists of a unique alphanumerical identifier, a common name, synonyms (if applicable), and a definition. When a term has multiple meanings depending on species, the URLURLGO termURLURL uses a ""sensu"" tag to differentiate among them. For example, the enzyme fumarase has the URLURLGO termURLURL term GO:0004333, fumarate hydratase activity (fumarase activity), catalysis of the reaction: (S)-malate = fumarate + H2O. See GO
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GPI anchor</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
C-terminal post-translational modification of many eukaryotic proteins. The two fatty acids within the glycophosphatidylinositol (GPI) moiety anchor the protein to the outer leaflet of the plasma membrane. GPI-anchored proteins are believed to be involved in signal transduction and immune responses, as well as the pathobiology of many parasites
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Gametocyte</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Eukaryotic germ cell that divides by mitosis to generate other gametocytes or by meiosis to generate gametes. Male gametocytes are called spermatocytes, and female gametocytes are called oocytes. Term often used to describe gametocytes of Plasmodium
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GenBank protein record</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Protein sequence file in the GenBank database generally derived by translation of a related nucleotide record
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GenPept protein</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Protein record from the GenPept database at the URLURLGenPept proteinURLURL GenBank, which contains inferred translations of protein-coding sequences
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Gene</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Fundamental physical and functional unit of heredity. Ordered sequence of nucleotides located in a particular position on a particular chromosome that encodes a specific functional product, such as a protein or RNA molecule. A gene may have a number of parts, including the promoter region, untranslated regions (5' and 3' UTRs), introns, and exons<font color="red">Link an image? From SRT tool?</font>
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GeneDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Project developed by the Sanger Institute Pathogen Sequencing Unit (PSU) and aimed at developing and maintaining curated database resources for all projects handled by the PSU. The database is accessible at http://www.genedb.org
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Genetic markers</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Known DNA sequences that can be identified by a simple assay. Generally genetic variations caused by mutation or alterations in loci that can be observed, examples include restriction length polymorphisms (RFLPs), short tandem repeats (STRs), variable number tandem repeats (VNTRs), short DNA sequences surrounding single base-pair changes (single nucleotide polymorphisms, or SNPs) or longer microsatellite sequences
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Genomic context</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Location of a gene in the genome; can influence the expression of the gene and functional interactions of the gene expression products. In this database, genes are depicted on individual gene pages with their surrounding genomic region and its annotation
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Genotyped SNPs</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) identified during genotyping of individual Toxoplasma and Plasmodium strains. See SNP genotyping<font color="red">Brian, anything to add?</font>
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Genotyping</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Process of determining the genotype of an individual with a biological assay using PCR, DNA sequencing, or hybridization to DNA microarrays or beads. Provides a measurement of the genetic variation between members of a species
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">GiardiaDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">HMM</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Hidden Markov model. Statistical model in which the system being modeled is assumed to be a Markov process with unknown parameters, and the challenge is to determine the hidden parameters from the observable parameters. The extracted model parameters can then be used to perform further analysis, for example for pattern recognition applications
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Homolog</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
"Related by evolutionary descent, either between species (ortholog) or within a species (paralog)
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Hydropathy</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Hydropathicity. Degree to which a peptide or protein is likely to be soluble in water. Protein hydropathy plots can be useful in predicting transmembrane domains, potential antigenic sites, and regions that are likely to be exposed on the protein's surface
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Intergenic region</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Stretch of DNA located between genes that may act to regulate gene expression
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Intersect</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Similar to the URLURLIntersectURLURL operator "AND" (see Boolean), an action used in the query history to find items that are common to two query result sets. For example, to search for items that appear in both result set X and result Y, type, "X INTERSECT Y"
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Join</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Similar to the URLURLJoinURLURL operator "UNION" (see Boolean), an action used in the query history to combine query sets. For example, to conbine result sets X and Y, type, "X JOIN Y"
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">KEGG map</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Metabolic or regulatory interaction pathway generated by the Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) or by the use of their tools. (http://www.genome.jp/kegg/)
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Locus</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Position on a chromosome of a gene, feature (such as a telomere), or other chromosomal marker; also, the DNA at that position. The use of locus is sometimes restricted to mean expressed DNA regions
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Low complexity</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Pertaining to sequence regions that have an unusually repetitive nature (for example, a protein sequence of low complexity might look like PPTDPPPPKKDGGPPL, and a low-complexity nucleotide sequence might be AAATAAAAAAAAATAAAAAAATTA). Low-complexity regions can create problems in sequence similarity searching by causing artifactual hits. For this reason, filters are often used to remove low-complexity sequences. URLURLLow complexityURLURL Low complexity regions are also those regions involved in antigenic variation in apicomplexan parasites
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Mass spec data</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Mass spectrometry data. Mass spectrometry is an analytical technique used to measure the mass-to-charge ratios of small molecules in several applications, including identification of proteins or peptides. In our databases, the Identify genes by Mass Spec Evidence query is used to identify genes that have evidence of protein expression based on mass spec data
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Metabolic pathways</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Series of chemical reactions occurring within a cell and often catalyzed by enzymes. Ina pathway, a molecule is often changed or modified into another product, which can be stored by the cell, used as a metabolic product, or used to initiate another pathway
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Microarray</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Microscopic array of biological molecules (for example, DNA or protein) used to determine the presence and/or amount (referred to as quantitation) of other biomolecules (other proteins, transcripts, etc.) in biological samples
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Microsatellite</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Polymorphic locus in nuclear and organellar DNA that consists of repeating units of 1-4 base pairs in length. Mostly neutral and codominant, microsatellites are used as molecular markers and to study gene dosage (looking for duplications or deletions of a particular genetic region). Also known as or simple sequence repeats (SSRs)
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Microsatellite map</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Map of microsatellite locations and linkages on a genome. See Microsatellite
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Mitochondrion</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Organelle responsible for respiration in a eukaryotic cell. Proteins required for mitochondrial function are encoded both in the nucleus and within the smaller mitochondrial genome
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Motif search</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Tool used to identify and locate sequence patterns (motifs) in protein and nucleic acid sequences. In our databases, this flexible search can be based on the general characteristics of the pattern and not solely on specific sequences, e.g. Cys-[9-11aa of anything]-Cys, or Leu-Leu-[basic residue]-Val. This allows the user to query based on previously undescribed motifs
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">NCBI</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
National Center for Biotechnology Information. Established in 1988 as a national resource for molecular biology information, NCBI creates public databases, conducts research in computational biology, develops software tools for analyzing genome data, and disseminates biomedical information - all for the better understanding of molecular processes affecting human health and disease
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Nonredundant protein DB (NRDB)</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Peptide sequence database containing all nonidentical protein sequences from the same speceis extracted from GenPept, URLURLNonredundant protein DB (NRDB)URLURL RefSeq, Swiss-Prot, and PRF databases. Used for URLURLNonredundant protein DB (NRDB)URLURL protein database searches because its smaller size results in shorter search times and more meaningful statistics
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Oligo</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Oligonucleotide. Short sequence of DNA or RNA, typically of 20-70 nucleotides
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Oligonucleotide microarray</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Collection of microscopic oligonucleotide spots arrayed on a solid surface by covalent attachment to chemically suitable matrices. Used for expression profiling, the monitoring of the expression levels of hundreds or thousands of genes simultaneously. Probes for oligonucleotide microarrays are designed to match parts of known or predicted mRNAs
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">OrthoMCL</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Genome-scale algorithm for grouping orthologous protein sequences. It provides genes shared by two or more species/genomes and also genes representing species-specific gene expansion families. Therefore, it serves as a utility for automated eukaryotic genome annotation and phylogenetic profiling. Available at http://orthomcl.cbil.upenn.edu
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Ortholog</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Same gene in different organisms; having evolved from the same ancestral locus
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Ortholog group</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Orthologous genes shared by group of organisms; the group of genes can also contain paralogs
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Orthology-based phylogenetic profile</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Tool used to find genes that are present or not present in a desired group of organisms on the tree of life (currently computed for 81 complete genomes); The user has control over the profile and whether or not genes must be found, or not found in any particular group of organisms, e.g. in Apicomplexa but not mammals. URLURLOrthology-based phylogenetic profileURLURL Taxa can also be marked as indifferent, i.e. it doesn't matter if the gene is also found in plants. URLURLOrthology-based phylogenetic profileURLURL URLURLOrthology-based phylogenetic profileURLURL and paralog relationships are determined with the URLURLOrthology-based phylogenetic profileURLURL algorithm
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">PATS</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Neural network analysis tool that identifies amino acid sequences within a query sequence that are potentially targeted to the apicoplast matrix of Plasmodium falciparum
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">PDB 3D structure</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Three-dimensional macromolecular structure in the Protein Data Bank (PDB) (http://www.pdb.org). URLURLPDB 3D structureURLURL obtained by one of three methods: X-ray crystallography (over 80%), solution nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) (about 16%), or theoretical modeling (2%). A few structures were determined by other methods
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">PROSITE motif</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Protein sequence pattern or profile derived from multiple alignments of homologous sequences and stored in the PROSITE database, an annotated collection of motif descriptors dedicated to the identification of protein families and domains
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Paralog</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Related by gene duplication within a genome; originated by duplication and then diverged from the parent copy by mutation and selection or drift
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Pearson correlation</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Pearson Product Moment Correlation, the most common measure of the correlation between two variables. Reflects the degree of linear relationship between two variables and ranges from +1 to -1, with a correlation of +1 indicating a perfect positive linear relationship between variables
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Peptide mass fingerprinting</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Analytical technique for protein identification wherein an unknown protein of interest is cleaved into peptides by a protease such as trypsin, and the peptides resulting from this cleavage are analyzed using a mass spectrometric method such as MALDI-TOF or ESI-TOF. The masses derived for the peptides are then compared to a database containing known protein sequences or even to the genome. Computer programs theoretically cut the protein sequences in the database into peptides with the same protease (for example trypsin), and calculate the absolute masses of the peptides from each protein. They then compare the masses of the peptides of the unknown protein to the theoretical peptide masses of each protein encoded in the genome. The results are statistically analyzed to find the best match
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Pfam domain</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
"Conserved protein region in the Pfam database (http://pfam.janelia.org), a collection of multiple sequence alignments and hidden Markov models covering many common protein families. The alignments may represent evolutionarily conserved structures that may shed light on protein function. Profile hidden Markov models (profile HMMs) built from the Pfam alignments can be useful for associating a new protein to a known protein family, even if the homology is weak. Unlike standard pairwise alignment methods (for example, URLURLPfam domainURLURL and FASTA), Pfam HMMs deal sensibly with multidomain proteins
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Phylogeny</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Historical relationships among lineages of organisms or their parts, including their genes
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">PlasmoAP</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Algorithm/tool that predicts the the liklihood that a protein sequence is targetted to the apicoplast. It provides the position of signal peptide cleavage sites in amino acid sequences if targetting is predicted
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">PlasmoCyc</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Database/utility built by analyzing the genomes of the Plasmodium species in URLURLPlasmoCycURLURL with SRI International's pathway tools; used for searching and visualizing Plasmodium metabolic pathway information
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">PlasmoDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">ProDom</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Database of protein domain families generated from the global comparison of all available protein sequences (http://prodom.prabi.fr)
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Promoter</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Regulatory region of DNA located upstream (towards the 5' region) of a gene and providing a control point for regulated gene transcription
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Protein-coding</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Capable of encoding a protein sequence; generally refers to a sequence of DNA
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Proteomics</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
The large-scale study of proteins, particularly of the full set of proteins encoded by a genome
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Pseudogene</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Defunct relatives of known genes that have lost their protein-coding ability or are otherwise no longer expressed in the cell. Although they may have some gene-like features (such as promoters, CpG islands, and splice sites), they are nonetheless considered nonfunctional due to their lack of protein-coding ability resulting from various genetic disablements (stop codons, frameshifts, or a lack of transcription) or their inability to function as an RNA (such as with URLURLPseudogeneURLURL pseudogenes)
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">PubCrawler</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Free service that scans daily updates to the URLURLPubCrawlerURLURL Medline (PubMed) and GenBank databases and alerts users to any relevant updates. Available at http://pubcrawler.gen.tcd.ie/
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Query</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Sequence or term used in a database search. For example, the sequence submitted for a URLURLQueryURLURL search is the query sequence
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">RNA predictions Predictions of genes that encode non-protein encoding RNA's such as tRNA, snoRNA, rRNA, etc</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">RefSeq mRNA</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Nonredundant mRNA sequence in the RefSeq database. RefSeq mRNA sequences with an NM_XXXXXX accession are curated sequences and are therefore considered more reliable than those with XM_XXXXXX accessions (predicted mRNA sequences)
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">RefSeq noncoding RNA</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Nonredundant noncoding RNA (ncRNA) sequence in the RefSeq database. RefSeq URLURLRefSeq noncoding RNAURLURL sequences with an NR_XXXXXX accession are curated sequences and are therefore considered more reliable than those with XR_XXXXXX accessions (predicted URLURLRefSeq noncoding RNAURLURL sequences). See ncRNA
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">RefSeq protein</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Nonredundant protein sequence in the RefSeq database. RefSeq protein sequences with NP_XXXXXX accessions are curated sequences and are therefore considered more reliable than those with XP_XXXXXX accessions (predicted protein sequences)
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">RefSeqs</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
NCBI reference sequences. A curated nonredundant collection of sequences representing genomes, transcripts, and proteins as annotated by by NCBI. The annotation in these records can be and often is URLURLRefSeqsURLURL different from the original GenBank submission, which is at time not updated as new information is learned
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Repeat regions</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Sequences present in many identical or highly similar copies in the genome
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">SAGE tags</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Serial analysis of gene expression (SAGE) tags. Short (14-nucleotide) sequences found within mRNA, the relative abundance of which indicates the level of expression of the mRNA containing that tag
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">SNP density</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Amount URLURLSNP densityURLURL or number of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in a region of the genome
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">SNP genotyping</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Identifying and mapping single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in an effort to determine the genotype members of a species. URLURLSNP genotypingURLURL usually consist of two alleles (where the rare allele frequency is ? 1%), are evolutionarily conserved, and are the most common type of genetic variation. See Genotyping
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">SNPs</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Single nucleotide polymorphisms. Small genetic changes or variations that can occur within a DNA sequence, for example when a single nucleotide, such as an A, replaces one of the other three nucleotide letters—C, G, or T. Most SNPs are found outside of coding sequences, but SNPs found within a coding sequence are more likely to alter the biological function of a protein. SNPs may be synonymous (generating a conservative change not altering the amino acid sequence) or they can be non-synonymous and change the amino acid that is encoded
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Scaffolds</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
In genomic mapping, a series of contigs that are in the right order and orientation, but not necessarily connected in one continuous stretch of sequence. See Contig
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Sequence similarity</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Degree of similarity between two or more protein or nucleotide sequences
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Signal peptide</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Short (3-60 amino acids) peptide sequence that directs the posttranslational transport of a protein to certain organelles or for secretion
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">SignalP</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Program that predicts the presence and location of signal peptide cleavage sites in amino acid sequences from Gram-positive and -negative prokaryotes and eukaryotes. The method incorporates a prediction of cleavage sites and a signal peptide/nonsignal peptide prediction based on a combination of several artificial neural networks and hidden Markov models
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Strand</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
One half of the DNA helix; string or stretch of covalently linked nucleotides
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Subtract</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Similar to the URLURLSubtractURLURL operator "NOT" (see Boolean), an action used in the query history to remove items from one result set that occur in another result set. For example, to remove items that exist in set Y from those in set X, type, "X SUBTRACT Y"
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Syntenic</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Loci located on the same chromosome but not necessarily linked. For example, genes that are part of a syntenic group share a common chromosomal location. Also used to refer to conservation of gene order across species
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">TIGR</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
The Institute for Genomic Research, a nonprofit center dedicated to deciphering and analyzing genomes
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">TM domains</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
See transmembrane domain
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">TWINSCAN gene models</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Gene models generated using TWINSCAN, a tool that integrates traditional probability models (such as those underlying GENSCAN and FGENESH) with information from alignments between two genomes. TWINSCAN is based on the idea that functional sequences show different patterns of evolutionary conservation than sequences under little selective pressure, such as the central regions of introns. TWINSCAN is designed for the analysis of high-throughput genomic sequences containing an unknown number of genes"
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Telomere</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Nucleoprotein complexes that constitute the physical ends of linear eukaryotic chromosomes and that have important functions, primarily in the protection, replication, and stabilization of the chromosome ends. Telomeres often contain lengthy stretches of tandemly repeated simple DNA sequences composed of a G-rich strand and a C-rich strand (called terminal repeats). These terminal repeats are highly conserved. Often sequences adjacent to the telomeric repeats are highly polymorphic, are rich in DNA repetitive elements (termed subtelomeric repeats), and in some cases, genes have been found in the proterminal regions of chromosomes
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">TigrScan gene</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Gene model generated using TigrScan, a gene-finding tool based on the generalized hidden Markov model framework, similar to GENSCAN and Genie. It is highly reconfigurable and includes software for retraining
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">ToxoCyc</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Database/utility built by analyzing the Toxoplasma gondii genome with SRI International's pathway tools; used for searching and visualizing Toxoplasma metabolic pathway information
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">ToxoDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Translation</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Synthesis of protein from an mRNA template
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Transmembrane domain</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Three-dimensional protein structure that is thermodynamically stable in a membrane. This may be a single alpha helix, a stable complex of several transmembrane alpha helices, a transmembrane beta barrel, a beta-helix of gramicidin A, or any other structure. Transmembrane domains average 20 amino acid residues in length, though they may be much smaller or much longer
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Transmembrane protein</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Protein that spans an entire biological membrane
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">TrichDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">UTR</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Untranslated region. Section of messenger RNA (mRNA) that either precedes (5' UTR) or follows (3' UTR) the coding region and is not itself translated. The UTR contains several regulatory regions, including the polyadenylation (polyA) site in the 3' UTR, sequences involved in the initiation of translation (in the 5' UTR), and binding regions for proteins and other regulatory molecules in both the 3' and 5' UTR
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">UniGene</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
"Project and database at URLURLUniGeneURLURL aimed at defining gene-oriented clusters of expressed sequence tags (ESTs). Sets of ESTs are clustered based on strong sequence homology in an attempt to define a specific, nonredundant cluster for each transcript in a tissue or genome. Each UniGene cluster contains sequences that represent a unique gene in addition to information about the tissue types in which the gene has been expressed and map location 
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Wildcard character</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Character used to substitute for any other character or characters in a string
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">Xenolog</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
A gene found in unrelated species that is related by gene transfer rather than common vertical descent
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">amitochondriate</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">blastn</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Version of the basic local alignment search tool (BLAST) used to compare a nucleotide query sequence against a nucleotide sequence database
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">blastp</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Version of the basic local alignment search tool (BLAST) used to compare a protein query sequence against a protein sequence database
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">blastx</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Version of the basic local alignment search tool (BLAST) used to compare a nucleotide query sequence translated in all reading frames against a protein sequence database
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">cDNA</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Complementary DNA. DNA molecule synthesized by the enzyme reverse transcriptase using an mRNA as template
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">cDNA microarray</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Collection of microscopic URLURLcDNA microarrayURLURL spots commonly representing single genes and arrayed on a solid surface (commonly glass slides) by covalent attachment to chemically suitable matrices. Used for expression profiling, the monitoring of the expression levels of hundreds or thousands of genes simultaneously
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">ePCR</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Electronic PCR (polymerase chain reaction). Computational procedure used to check for uniqueness in spacing and number of primer binding sites within DNA sequences. Searches for subsequences that closely match a set of PCR primers and that have the correct order, orientation, and spacing to make a PCR product. Used to check the expected length of a PCR product, which can provide information regarding unexpected repetitive sequences
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">ncRNA</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Noncoding RNA. Any RNA that is not translated into a protein. Includes transfer RNA (tRNA), ribosomal RNA (rRNA), small RNAs such as snoRNAs, microRNAs, siRNAs and piRNAs, as well as long ncRNAs
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">nucmer</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">rRNA</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Ribosomal RNA. Component of the ribosomes, which function in protein synthesis
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">snRNA</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Small nuclear RNA. Class of small RNA molecules found within the nucleus, transcribed by RNA polymerase II or III, and involved in a variety of important processes such as RNA splicing (removal of introns from hnRNA), regulation of transcription factors (7SK RNA) or RNA polymerase II (B2 RNA), and maintaining telomeres. They are always associated with specific proteins, and the complexes are referred to as small nuclear ribonucleoproteins (snRNP) or snurps. These elements are rich in uridine content. A large group of snRNAs known as small nucleolar RNAs (snoRNAs) are small RNA molecules that play an essential role in RNA biogenesis and chemical modification of ribosomal RNAs (rRNAs) and other RNA genes (tRNA and snRNAs). They are located in the nucleus and the cajal bodies of eukaryotic cells (the major sites of RNA synthesis)
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">tRNA</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Transfer RNA. Small RNA chain (73-93 nucleotides) that transfers a specific amino acid to a growing polypeptide chain at the ribosomal site of protein synthesis during translation. A three-base region, the anticodon, pairs to the corresponding three-base codon region on the template mRNA. Each type of tRNA molecule can be attached to only one type of amino acid, but because the genetic code contains multiple codons that specify the same amino acid, tRNA molecules bearing different anticodons may also carry the same amino acid
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">tblastn</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Version of the basic local alignment search tool (BLAST) used to compare a protein query sequence against a translated nucleotide sequence database
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="term">tblastx</attribute>
       <attribute name="definition">
         <![CDATA[
Version of the basic local alignment search tool (BLAST) used to compare the six-frame translations of a nucleotide query sequence against the six-frame translations of a nucleotide sequence database
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

</xmlAnswer>
