<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE xml [
  <!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"> 
  <!ENTITY lt   "&#60;"> 
  <!ENTITY gt   "&#62;">
  <!ENTITY sl   "&#47;">
]>

<xmlAnswer>


   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Overview</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">overview</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">   
         <![CDATA[
This document provides a high-level overview of the software infrastructure utilized by the EuPathDB BRC to load, integrate and provide data to users.  The links provide details for each of the components summarized here.  If you would like a PDF of this information, please download from the following link.
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
  <li><a href="/documents/EuPathDB_Infrastructure_combined.pdf">EuPathDB_Infrastructure_combined.pdf</a>
</ul>
</div>
       ]]>

       </attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Data Loading and Database Schema</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">data</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">   
         <![CDATA[

We use the <b>G</b>enomics <b>U</b>nified <b>S</b>chema (GUS) database schema and data loading infrastructure available at <a href="http://www.gusdb.org">GusDB.org</a>.  This includes not only a comprehensive database schema for integrating and representing genomic and functional (or post) genomic data but also tools for loading said data into that system.  We have made some extensions to the schema and tools for EuPathDB specific purposes primarily to generate de-normalized views of the data for query optimization purposes.</p><br>
<p>
Our data are all stored in Oracle11g databases.  Our software infrastructure also supports PostgreSQL but we have some Oracle specific SQL constructs in our model that would need to be changed in order to run successfully in PostgreSQL.  </p><br>
<p>
We load all data using an in house engineered workflow system called ReFlow.  Documentation and code for ReFlow can be found on the <a href="http://code.google.com/p/reflow-genomics/">ReFlow google code repository</a>.  Briefly, ReFlow is engineered to be an efficient graph based workflow system any step of which has the ability to be undone and subsequently rerun with updated data.  This was a significant requirement as it enables us to undo entire genomes when the annotation or underlying sequence changes.  This results in automated removal of all data dependent on that genome and when it is re-run with the new annotation, all dependent data are recomputed and reloaded automatically, thus greatly improving our ability to keep these complex databases up-to-date.  
A significant component of our dataloading system is our ability to automate the running of large compute tasks on compute clusters located at the University of Pennsylvania and the University of Georgia.  The ReFlow workflow system utilizes another piece of software developed at the University of Pennsylvania to schedule, manage and monitor running tasks called <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fdocs.google.com%2Fdocument%2Fpub%3Fid%3D1BixZ5t2c0hnOZES-Rk2wG2loAQqclcmRj7AeKQjZMHA">DistribJob</a>.  DistribJob distributes tasks generated from a large input dataset such as a set of sequences to compute nodes in a cluster for analysis and retrieves and collates the results in an efficient manner.</p>
<br>
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.gusdb.org">GUS Schema and Tools</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="http://www.gusdb.org/SchemaBrowser/categoryList.htm">GUS Schema</a>
      <li><a href="http://www.gusdb.org/documentation/3.5/developers/developersguide.pdf">GUS developers guide</a>
    </ul>
  <li><a href="http://code.google.com/p/reflow-genomics/">ReFlow Workflow System</a>
  <li><a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fdocs.google.com%2Fdocument%2Fpub%3Fid%3D1BixZ5t2c0hnOZES-Rk2wG2loAQqclcmRj7AeKQjZMHA">DistribJob Cluster Task Management</a>
</ul>
</div>
       ]]>

       </attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Web Presentation System and User Interfaces</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">wdk</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">   
         <![CDATA[
<p>Our websites are based on code that we developed and have released to the community called the Strategies-WDK (Strategies Web Development Kit) which enables the graphical strategies search system.  You can download the software and see documentation for this toolkit at <a href="http://code.google.com/p/strategies-wdk/">Strategies-WDK google code website</a>.  This toolkit enables us to represent our data as an XML model which is then turned into the web interfaces that are presented to users using these tools.</p>
<br>
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
  <li><a href="http://code.google.com/p/strategies-wdk/">Strategies-WDK Website</a>
  <li><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1kmNWkkcInKoxxiuUJqbc4QPWuySQud0OuECJ2TmEMTo/pub">Strategies-WDK Documentation</a>
</ul>
</div>
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">System Hardware and Third Party Software</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">hardware</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">   
         <![CDATA[
<p>
EuPathDB maintains redundant database and content web servers at the University of Pennsylvania and the University of Georgia to minimize interruptions for our users during maintenance periods. Additionally EuPathDB compute and data loading servers are located at the University of Pennsylvania. 
<br><br>
Server configurations are coordinated and deployed through Puppet automation software (<a href="http://puppetlabs.com/" target="_blank">http://puppetlabs.com/</a>). Custom infrastructure software is versioned and deployed through standard RPM/YUM mechanisms. When appropriate, software builds are automated using Jenkins Continuous Integration Server (<a href="http://jenkins-ci.org/" target="_blank">http://jenkins-ci.org/</a>) and deployed into an internal Sonatype Nexus (<a href="http://www.sonatype.org/nexus/" target="_blank">http://www.sonatype.org/nexus/</a>) repository.  
<br><br>
System infrastructure statistics (CPU load, I/O, etc) are gathered with collectd (<a href="http://collectd.org/" target="_blank">http://collectd.org/</a>) and in-house applications and feed to Graphite (<a href="http://graphite.wikidot.com/" target="_blank">http://graphite.wikidot.com/</a>) for human review. Nagios (<a href="http://www.nagios.org/" target="_blank">http://www.nagios.org/</a>) provides notifications of system degradations.
<br><br>
Both Universities also maintain large compute clusters that are heavily utilized by EuPathDB in order to analyze and load incoming data in a timely fashion. The linked document below describes our actual hardware and includes a list of third-party software required in order to analyze, load and present data via our websites.

</p>
<br>
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
  <li><a href="/documents/EuPathDB_Hardware_3P_Software.pdf">Hardware and Third Party Software</a>
</ul>
</div>
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Community Interactions and Data Submission Policies</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">community</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">   
         <![CDATA[
<p>EuPathDB serves a global scientific community that demands direct active support and community involvement.   EuPathDB outreach activities include:</p><br>
 <div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
  <li>Organizing and running hands on training workshops and webinars (<a href="http://tinyurl.com/7qjxumg">Google Map</a>).
  <li>Developing educational material in the form of <a href="http://workshop.eupathdb.org/current/index.php?page=schedule">exercises</a> and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/EuPathDB/">online tutorials</a>.
  <li>Responding to support emails for users who contact us directly by clicking the "Contact Us" links in the header or footer of any EuPathDB webpage (average response time is 48 hours).
  <li>Holding semi-annual meetings with our <a href="showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.AboutAll#swg">Scientific Working Group</a> to discuss high-level goals and deliverables for the project.
  <li>Holding bimonthly conference calls with our <a href="showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.About#advisors">Scientific Advisory Groups</a> (these are organism specific, one per component site with TriTrypDB separated into three) to learn about new datasets, set priorities and share with the community current activities.
  <li>Attending national and international meetings with active participation in the form of posters, presentations or help desks.
  <li>Authoring <a href="http://www.eupathdb.org/eupathdb/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.EuPathDBPubs">peer reviewed manuscripts</a>.
  <li>Maintaining active social media presence in the form of a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/EuPathDB/133123003429972">FaceBook page</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/eupathdb">Twitter feed</a>.
  <li>Providing a clear <a href="/EuPathDB_datasubm_SOP.pdf">data handling and release policy</a> to investigators to encourage submission of data prepublication.
</ul>
</div>
       ]]>

       </attribute>
   </record>

 

</xmlAnswer>
