<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE xml [
  <!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"> 
  <!ENTITY lt   "&#60;"> 
  <!ENTITY gt   "&#62;">
  <!ENTITY sl   "&#47;">
]>

<xmlAnswer>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Add Step</attribute>
       <attribute name="image">/images/strathelp/addstep.jpg</attribute>
       <attribute name="body">
Running a search places you in the Search Strategy system.  Your search is the first "step" of a new strategy.  To refine your result set, add steps to the strategy as needed.
Click the Add Step button to add a step.  You will be prompted to choose a search.  Next you will be prompted to combine the new search with the previous results (using intersect, union or minus).  The new results reflect this combination.
We hope strategies help you get the most from the data!
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tip">
you can click Add Step to add a step to your strategy.
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="showTipAsDidYouKnow">true</attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">View prior steps</attribute>
       <attribute name="image">/images/strathelp/viewresults.jpg</attribute>
       <attribute name="body">
To view the results of a prior search or combination, click on a result count in a step box.
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tip">
you can see results of a previous step by clicking on the number in its box.
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="showTipAsDidYouKnow">true</attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Step actions menu</attribute>
       <attribute name="image">/images/strathelp/adjuststep.jpg</attribute>
       <attribute name="body">
For a menu of actions/properties for a step's search click on the search name in the step box.
For a menu of actions/properties for how it is combined with the prior step, click on the Venn diagram.
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tip">
you can get a menu of step actions by clicking on the plus icon, the step name or the Venn diagram.
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="showTipAsDidYouKnow">true</attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Branched (nested) strategy</attribute>
       <attribute name="image">/images/strathelp/nestedstep.jpg</attribute>
       <attribute name="body">
Simple strategies are linear.  More advanced strategies include branches.  (For example one step may need to union two searches.)  The trick is to "nest" a strategy within a step.
Click the step name to get a menu.  Choose "Make Nested Strategy."  Now that step appears expanded in a panel below.  All steps added to that panel will be nested into the step in the panel above.  The whole nested strategy acts as a single step in the parent strategy.
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tip">
you can branch a strategy.  Choose Make Nested Strategy in the step actions menu.
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="showTipAsDidYouKnow">true</attribute>
   </record>


</xmlAnswer>
