<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE xml [
  <!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"> 
  <!ENTITY lt   "&#60;"> 
  <!ENTITY gt   "&#62;">
  <!ENTITY sl   "&#47;">
]>

<xmlAnswer>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">General Information</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">generalinfo</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

EuPathDB (formerly ApiDB) is an integrated database 
covering the eukaryotic pathogens in the genera listed in our <a href="processQuestion.do?questionFullName=OrganismQuestions.GenomeDataTypes">Data Summary</a> page.
<br>
While these organisms are supported by a taxon-specific database/website built upon the same infrastructure, the EuPathDB portal offers an 
entry point to all of these resources, and the opportunity to leverage orthology for searches across genera.
<br><br>
The EuPathDB databases are funded by NIAID and they have strict guidelines as to which organisms we can support.  EuPathDB is one of four <a href="http://www.niaid.nih.gov/labsandresources/resources/dmid/brc/Pages/default.aspx">NIH funded bioinformatics resource centers</a>.  Mainly we are to incorporate any eukaryotic pathogen that is deemed emerging or re-emerging (see <a href="http://www3.niaid.nih.gov/topics/emerging/list.htm">list</a>).  We also have some organisms that are not on the list, those were either added in the past on the behest of the community and additional funding (such as TrichDB), organisms that are related to emerging or re-emerging pathogen (such as Plasmodium or Neospora) and the trypanosomatids (funded as a pilot project by the Bill and Melinda Gates foundation).
<br><br>
The EuPathDB family of databases is expected to expand further over the coming years, incorporating new species including the Amoebozoa 
(Entamoeba, Acanthamoeba), Microsporidia, and additional Apicomplexans, Kinetoplastida and Diplomonads. 
Of course, we continue collecting data that are being deposited at an ever-increasing rate, including additional genome sequences, microarray data, probe-based hybridization and sequencing data (e.g. ChIP-chip and RNA-Seq), proteomics data, isolate data, phenotype information and metabolomic data.
<br><br>
For a list of the data integrated into EuPathDB and the related publications please see <a href="app/answer/DatasetQuestions.AllDatasets" class="blue"> Data Sets</a>.
<br><br>
Please check our annual <a href="http://workshop.eupathdb.org/current/index.php?page=schedule">EuPathDB Workshop at UGA</a> exercises to see the scope of data and functionality in our sites.  


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Data Statistics</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">stats</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

<div id="cirbulletlist"><ul>
<li>The <a href = "processQuestion.do?questionFullName=OrganismQuestions.GenomeDataTypes">EuPathDB Data Summary</a> provides an overview of the content in EuPathDB across sites, all organisms and data types covered.
<li>The <a href="processQuestion.do?questionFullName=OrganismQuestions.GeneMetrics">EuPathDB Gene Metrics Table</a> summarizes the number of genes for the organisms currently available in EuPathDB, by various datatypes.
</ul></div>

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Understanding Data</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">protocols_methods</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

For a list of the data integrated into EuPathDB and the related publications please see <a href="app/answer/DatasetQuestions.AllDatasets" class="blue"> Data Sets</a>.

<br><br>
<h4>EST Assemblies</h4>
EST assemblies are transcript predictions based on genome alignments. 
ESTs are obtained from dbEST and from researchers who generously provide 
additional libraries. ESTs are cleaned prior to use; leading or trailing 
poly A or T sequences are trimmed and vector sequences are masked. ESTs 
greater than 50 bases long are used for BLAT alignment (Kent,W.J, 2002. 
Genome Research. 12:656-664) to same species genome sequences with a 
threshold of 90% minimum sequence identity, minimum score of 30, and the 
maximum intron length adjusted for the species. The ESTs are then 
clustered into disjoint sets based on the proximity and quality of their 
alignments, only the best alignments with a 95% minimum percent identity 
are used for clustering. Clusters of ESTs are then assembled and 
consensus sequences produced using the CAP4 assembly program (X. Huang 
and Madan, A., 1999. Genome Res. 9:868-877). Finally, the predicted 
consensus transcripts are themselves aligned to the genome.


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


    <record>
       <attribute name="title">Funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

The Eukaryotic Pathogen Database (EuPathDB) has been developed as a 
Bioinformatics Resource Center (BRC), with support from the US National 
Institutes of Health (NIH).  Additional funding for a kinetoplastid component 
(TriTrypDB) was recently provided by the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, in 
coordination with independent support for kinetoplastid annotation from the 
Wellcome Trust.


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


<record>
       <attribute name="title">Data Access Policy</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">use</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

The data at this site is provided freely for public use, through
the contributions of many researchers including those involved in
generating the genome sequences. The data is not guaranteed to be
accurate as it often reflects the results of ongoing research.
When using data obtained from EuPathDB, it is important to cite
the original publications and contributors of that data and
EuPathDB. Please see Citing EuPathDB below.
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Citing EuPathDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">citing</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

Much of the data in EuPathDB is provided by independent
researchers.  Please cite them if you use their data. 
For a list of the data integrated into EuPathDB and the related publications please see <a href="app/answer/DatasetQuestions.AllDatasets" class="blue"> Data Sets</a>.


<br><br>
When citing EuPathDB itself, please use:
<br>
<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/sites/entrez?db=pubmed&cmd=search&term=17098930">
ApiDB: integrated resources for the apicomplexan bioinformatics resource center.</a>
2007 Jan;35(NAR Database issue):D427-30. Aurrecoechea C, et al. (to be updated soon)
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>




</xmlAnswer>
