<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE xml [
  <!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"> 
  <!ENTITY lt   "&#60;"> 
  <!ENTITY gt   "&#62;">
  <!ENTITY sl   "&#47;">
]>

<xmlAnswer>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">General Information</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">generalinfo</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

EuPathDB (formerly ApiDB) is an integrated database 
covering the eukaryotic pathogens in the genera <i>Cryptosporidium</i>, <i>Giardia</i>, 
<i>Leishmania</i>, <i>Neospora</i>, <i>Plasmodium</i>, <i>Toxoplasma</i>, <i>Trichomonas</i> and 
<i>Trypanosoma</i>.  While each of these groups is supported by a taxon-specific 
database built upon the same infrastructure, the EuPathDB portal offers an 
entry point to all of these resources, and the opportunity to leverage orthology 
for searches across genera.
<br><br>
The EuPathDB family of databases is expected to expanding further over 
the coming years, incorporate new species including the Amoebozoa 
(Entamoeba, Acanthamoebs), Microsporidia, and additional Apicomplexans, 
Kinetoplastida and Diplomonads.
<br><br>
Of course, we continue collecting data  that are being deposited at an ever-increasing rate, including additional 
genome sequences, microarray data, probe-based hybridization and sequencing 
data (e.g. ChIP-chip and RNA-Seq), proteomics data, isolate data, phenotype 
information, metabolomic data, etc.


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Organisms</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">organisms</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
<ul>
<li> <i>Cryptosporidium</i>
<li> <i>Giardia</i> 
<li> <i>Leishmania</i> 
<li> <i>Neospora</i> 
<li> <i>Plasmodium</i> 
<li>  <i>Toxoplasma</i> 
<li> <i>Trichomonas</i>
<li> <i>Trypanosoma</i>
</ul>

<br>The <a href = "/a/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.GenomeDataType">EuPathDB Data Summary</a> provides an overview of the content in EuPathDB across sites, all organisms and data types covered.

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

<record>
       <attribute name="title">Data Statistics</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">stats</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

<div id="cirbulletlist"><ul>
<li>The <a href = "/a/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.GenomeDataType">EuPathDB Data Summary</a> provides an overview of the content in EuPathDB across sites, all organisms and data types covered.
<li>The <a href="/a/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.GeneMetrics">EuPathDB Gene Metrics Table</a> summarizes the number of genes for the organisms currently available in EuPathDB, by various datatypes.
</ul></div>

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Understanding Data: Protocols and Methods</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">protocols_methods</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

For detail on Data Sources and Methods please access specific component sites information:
<center>
<table width="50%" border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="2">


<tr valign="top">
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://cryptodb.org" style="color:#003366"><b>CryptoDB.org:</b></a></font></td>
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://cryptodb.org/cryptodb/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.DataSources" >Data Sources</a>,&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://cryptodb.org/cryptodb/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.Methods"> Methods</a>,&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://cryptodb.org/static/SOP/">SOPs for annotation.</a></font></td>
</tr>

<tr valign="top">
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://giardiadb.org" style="color:#003366"><b>GiardiaDB.org:</b></a></font></td>
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://giardiadb.org/giardiadb/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.DataSources">Data Sources</a>,&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://giardiadb.org/giardiadb/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.Methods">Methods</a>
</td>
</tr>

<tr valign="top">
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://plasmodb.org" style="color:#003366"><b>PlasmoDB.org:</b></a></font></td>
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://plasmodb.org/plasmo/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.DataSources">Data Sources</a>,&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://plasmodb.org/plasmo/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.Methods">Methods</a>
</td>
</tr>

<tr valign="top">
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://toxodb.org" style="color:#003366"><b>ToxoDB.org:</b></a></font></td>
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://toxodb.org/toxo/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.DataSources">Data Sources</a>,&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://toxodb.org/toxo/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.Methods">Methods</a>
</td>
</tr>

<tr valign="top">
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://trichdb.org" style="color:#003366"><b>TrichDB.org:</b></a></font></td>
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://trichdb.org/trichdb/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.DataSources">Data Sources</a>,&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://trichdb.org/trichdb/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.Methods">Methods</a>
</td>
</tr>

<tr valign="top">
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://tritrypdb.org" style="color:#003366"><b>TriTrypDB.org:</b></a></font></td>
    <td align="left" ><font face="Arial,Helvetica"><a href="http://tritrypdb.org/tritrypdb/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.DataSources">Data Sources</a>,&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://tritrypdb.org/tritrypdb/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.Methods">Methods</a>
</td>
</tr>

</table>
</center>
<br><br>
<h4>EST Assemblies</h4>
EST assemblies are transcript predictions based on genome alignments. 
ESTs are obtained from dbEST and from researchers who generously provide 
additional libraries. ESTs are cleaned prior to use; leading or trailing 
poly A or T sequences are trimmed and vector sequences are masked. ESTs 
greater than 50 bases long are used for BLAT alignment (Kent,W.J, 2002. 
Genome Research. 12:656-664) to same species genome sequences with a 
threshold of 90% minimum sequence identity, minimum score of 30, and the 
maximum intron length adjusted for the species. The ESTs are then 
clustered into disjoint sets based on the proximity and quality of their 
alignments, only the best alignments with a 95% minimum percent identity 
are used for clustering. Clusters of ESTs are then assembled and 
consensus sequences produced using the CAP4 assembly program (X. Huang 
and Madan, A., 1999. Genome Res. 9:868-877). Finally, the predicted 
consensus transcripts are themselves aligned to the genome.



       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

<record>
       <attribute name="title">Understanding Downloads</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">downloads</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
There are several kinds of downloads available in a EuPathDB site:
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
<li> Download files that have we create at release time. The link to access these files is under the menu item "Downloads", under "Data Files". These include fasta files for all available sequences, gff files with complete gene information, and other formats.
<li> Download files that are generated by running queries. From a result page (after running a query) a user can access the "Download Resuts" link, to a new page where a few different options are offered. The goal is to construct a file for download that include all IDs in the result; the user requests a file format and, in some formats, the user may request additional information about the result IDs.
<li> Download files that have been uploaded by the community in our websites, available under "Downloads" or "Community".
</ul>
</div>
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

  <record>
       <attribute name="title">Scientific Advisory Team</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">advisors</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

Each project in EuPathDB benefits from the advice and mentoring of people from each specific community.
<br><br>

<b>CryptoDB</b><br><br>
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
<li>Lihua Xiao (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, USA)
<li>Gregory Buck (Virginia Commonwealth University, USA)
<li>Giovanni Widmer (Tufts University, USA)
<li>Guan Zhu (Texas A&M University, USA)
</ul></div>
<br>
<b>GiardiaDB</b><br><br>
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
<li>John Samuelson (Boston University, USA)</li>
<li>Hilary Morrison (Marine Biological Laboratories, USA)</li>
<li>Adrian Hehl (University of Zürich, Switzerland)</li>
<li>Fran Gillin (University of California - San Diego, USA)</li>
<li>Scott Dawson (University of California - Davis, USA)</li>
</ul></div>
<br>
<b>PlasmoDB</b><br><br>
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
<li>John Adams (University of South Florida, USA)
<li>Stuart Ralph (University of Melbourne, Australia)
<li>Akhil Vaidya (Drexel University, USA)
<li>Andy Waters (University of Glasgow, United Kingdom)
</ul></div>
<br>
<b>ToxoDB</b><br><br>
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
<li>John Boothroyd (Stanford University, USA)
<li>Marc-Jan Gubbles (Boston College, USA)
<li>Vern B. Carruthers (University of Michigan, USA)
<li>Michael White (University of South Florida, USA)
</ul></div>
<br>
<b>TrichDB</b><br><br>
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
<li>
<li>
<li>
<li>
</ul></div>
<br><br>
<b>TriTrypDB</b><br><br>
<ul>
<li><div id="cirbulletlist"><ul><b><i>Leishmania</i></b>
     <li>Richard Burchmore (University of Glasgow, United Kingdom)
      <li>Barbara Papadopoulou (Laval University, Canada)
      <li>Jeremy Mottram (University of Glasgow, United Kingdom)
      <li>Angela Cruz (Universidade de São Paulo, Brazil)
    </ul></div><br>
<li><div id="cirbulletlist"><ul><b><i>T. cruzi</i></b>
     <li>John Kelly (London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, United Kingdom)
     <li>Sergio Schenkman (Universidade Federal de São Paulo, Brazil)
      <li>Rick tarleton (University of Georgia, USA)
      <li>Fernan Aguero (Universidad Nacional de General San Martín, Argentina)
      <li>Brent Weatherly (University of Georgia, USA)
     </ul></div><br>
<li><div id="cirbulletlist"><ul><b><i>T. brucei</i></b>
     <li>Vivian Bellofatto (New Jersey Medical School, USA)
     <li>Antonio Estevez (Institute of Parasitology and Biomedicine "López-Neyra", Spain)
      <li>George Cross (The Rockefeller University, USA)
      <li>Laurie Read (State University of Buffalo, USA)
       <li>March Field (University of Cambridge, United Kingdom)
      <li>Keith Gull (University of Oxford, United Kingdom)
</ul></div>
<br>
</ul>


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Acknowledgements</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">acks</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

EuPathDB wishes to acknowledge all the community members who
have contributed data (often pre-publication), entered user
comments or sent us their suggestions.
<br><br>
And the team behind EuPathDB:<br>
Cristina Aurrecoechea1, John Brestelli2,4, Brian P. Brunk2,7, Steve Fischer2,4, Bindu Gajria2,7, Xin Gao2,7, Alan Gingle3, Greg Grant2,4, Omar S. Harb2,7, Mark Heiges1, Frank Innamorato2,4, John Iodice2,4, Jessica C. Kissinger1,5, Eileen T. Kraemer6, Wei Li2,7, John A. Miller6, Vishal Nayak2,4, Cary Pennington1, Deborah F. Pinney2,4, David S. Roos7, Chris Ross1, Ganesh Srinivasamoorthy1, Christian J. Stoeckert Jr. 2,4, Ryan Thibodeau1, Charles Treatman2,7, Haiming Wang1
<br><br>
<ul>
<li>1Center for Tropical & Emerging Global Diseases, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602 USA
<li>2Penn Center for Bioinformatics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA 19104 USA
<li>3Center for Applied Genetic Technologies, University of Georgia, Athens, GA, 30602 USA
<li>4Department of Genetics, University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine, Philadelphia, PA 19104 USA
<li>5Department of Genetics, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602 USA
<li>6Department of Computer Science, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602 USA
<li>7Department of Biology, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA 19104 USA
</ul>

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

    <record>
       <attribute name="title">Funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

The Eukaryotic Pathogen Database (EuPathDB) has been developed as a 
Bioinformatics Resource Center (BRC), with support from the US National 
Institutes of Health (NIH).  Additional funding for a kinetoplastid component 
(TriTrypDB) was recently provided by the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, in 
coordination with independent support for kinetoplastid annotation from the 
Wellcome Trust.


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


<record>
       <attribute name="title">Data Access Policy</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">use</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

The data at this site is provided freely for public use, through
the contributions of many researchers including those involved in
generating the genome sequences. The data is not guaranteed to be
accurate as it often reflects the results of ongoing research.
When using data obtained from EuPathDB, it is important to cite
the original publications and contributors of that data and
EuPathDB. Please see Citing EuPathDB below.
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Citing EuPathDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">citing</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

Much of the data in EuPathDB is provided by independent
researchers.  Please cite them if you use their data.  For a list
of the data integrated into EuPathDB and the related
publications please access the "Data Sources" link, in each respective project (CryptoDB, GiardiaDB, etc) located on the menubar under the header of the any page.

<br><br>
When citing EuPathDB itself, please use:
<br>
<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/sites/entrez?db=pubmed&cmd=search&term=17098930">
ApiDB: integrated resources for the apicomplexan bioinformatics resource center.</a>
2007 Jan;35(NAR Database issue):D427-30. Aurrecoechea C, et al. (to be updated soon)
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

<record>
       <attribute name="title">Documents and Publications</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">docs_pubs</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

<table width='80%' align='center' cellpadding='2' cellspacing='0' border='0'>

<tr><td colspan="2"><font face="Arial,Helvetica">The <a href="/">Eukaryotic Pathogen Bioinformatics Resource Center (BRC)</a> designs, develops and maintains the EuPathDB, CryptoDB, GiardiaDB, PlasmoDB, ToxoDB and TrichDB websit
es.  These are publications by the scientists and staff involved in this BRC.
</font></td></tr>

<tr><td>

<div class='citations'>

<p>


<p>
 Aurrecoechea, C., J. Brestelli, B. P. Brunk, J. Dommer, S. Fischer, B. Gajria, X. Gao, A. Gingle, G. Grant, O. S. Harb, M. Heiges, F. Innamorato, J. Iodice, J. C. Kissinger, E. Kraemer, W. Li, J. A. Miller, V. Nayak, C. Penning
ton, D. F. Pinney, D. S. Roos, C. Ross, C. J. Stoeckert, Jr., C. Treatman, and H. Wang.<br>
 <b>PlasmoDB: a functional genomic database for malaria parasites.</b><br>
 Nucleic Acids Res. 2009. 37:D539-D543.<br>
[ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/gkn814">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/gkn814">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/gkn814">PDF</a> ]

<p>
 Aurrecoechea, C., J. Brestelli, B. P. Brunk, J. M. Carlton, J. Dommer, S. Fischer, B. Gajria, X. Gao, A. Gingle, G. Grant, O. S. Harb, M. Heiges, F. Innamorato, J. Iodice, J. C. Kissinger, E. Kraemer, W. Li, J. A. Miller, H. G.
 Morrison, V. Nayak, C. Pennington, D. F. Pinney, D. S. Roos, C. Ross, C. J. Stoeckert, Jr., S. Sullivan, C. Treatman, and H. Wang.<br>
 <b>GiardiaDB and TrichDB: integrated genomic resources for the eukaryotic protist pathogens Giardia lamblia and Trichomonas vaginalis.</b><br>
 Nucleic Acids Res. 2009. 37:D526-D530.<br>
[ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/gkn631">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/gkn631">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/gkn631">PDF</a> ]


<p>
 B. Gajria, A. Bahl, J. Brestelli, J. Dommer, S. Fischer, X. Gao, M. Heiges, J. Iodice, J. C. Kissinger, A. J. Mackey, et al.<br>
<b>ToxoDB: an integrated Toxoplasma gondii database resource.</b><br>
 Nucleic Acids Res. 2007. 36:D553-6. <br>
[ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/gkm981v1">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/gkm981v1">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/gkm981v1">PDF</a> ]


<p>
Cristina Aurrecoechea, Mark Heiges, Haiming Wang, Zhiming Wang, Steve Fischer, Philippa Rhodes, John Miller, Eileen Kraemer, Christian J. Stoeckert, Jr., David S. Roos and Jessica C. Kissinger.<br>
<b>ApiDB: integrated resources for the apicomplexan bioinformatics resource center.</b><br>
 Nucleic Acids Research. 2007. 35:D427-30.<br>
[ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/gkl880?ijkey=7QHavFAOdzzOSLM&keytype=ref">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/gkl880?ijkey=7QHavFAOdzzOSLM&keytype=ref">Full text</
a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/gkl880?ijkey=7QHavFAOdzzOSLM&keytype=ref">PDF</a> ]


<p>
Christian J. Stoeckert Jr., Steve Fisher, Jessica Kissinger, Mark Heiges, Cristina Aurrecoechea, Bindu Gajria, David S. Roos. <br>
<b>PlasmoDB v5: New Looks, New Genomes.</b><br>
Trends in Parasitology. 2006. 22(12): 543-546.<br>
[ <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?db=pubmed&cmd=Retrieve&dopt=AbstractPlus&list_uids=17029963&query_hl=1&itool=pubmed_docsum">Abstract</a> ]

<p>
Patricia L. Whetzel, Shailesh V. Date, Kobby Essien, Martin J. Fraunholz, Bindu Gajria, Gregory R. Grant, John Iodice, Jessica C. Kissinger, Philip T. Labo, Arthur J. Milgram, David S. Roos, and Christian J. Stoeckert Jr. <br>
<b>PlasmoDB: The Plasmodium Genomics and Functional Genomics Resource.</b><br>
In silico Genomics and Proteomics: Functional Annotation of Genomes and Proteins. Nicola Mulder and Rolf Apweiler (eds.). Nova Science Publishers. 2006. <br>


<p>
Haiming Wang, Yanqi Su, Aaron J. Mackey, Eileen T. Kraemer and Jessica C. Kissinger.<br>
<b>SynView: A GBrowse-compatible Approach to Visualizing Comparative Genome Data.</b><br>
Bioinformatics. 2006. 22(18):2308-2309<br>
[ <a href="http://bioinformatics.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/short/22/18/2308">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://bioinformatics.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/22/18/2308">Full text</a> |<a href="http://bioinformatics.oxford
journals.org/cgi/reprint/22/18/2308">PDF</a> | <a href="http://eupathdb.org/apps/SynView/">Supplement</a> ]

<p>
Heiges M, Wang H, Robinson E, Aurrecoechea C, Gao X, Kaluskar N, Rhodes P, Wang S, He CZ, Su Y, Miller J, Kraemer E, Kissinger JC. <br>
<b>CryptoDB: a <i>Cryptosporidium</i> bioinformatics resource update.</b><br>
Nucleic Acids Res. 2006 Jan 1;34:D419-22.<br>
[ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/34/suppl_1/D419">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/34/suppl_1/D419">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/re
print/34/suppl_1/D419">PDF</a> ]

<p>

Feng Chen, Aaron J. Mackey, Christian J. Stoeckert Jr. and David S. Roos.<br>
<b>OrthoMCL-DB: querying a comprehensive multi-species collection of ortholog groups.</b><br>
Nucleic Acids Res. 2006 Jan 1;34:D363-8.<br>
[ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/34/suppl_1/D363">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/34/suppl_1/D363">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/re
print/34/suppl_1/D363">PDF</a> ]

<p>
J.C. Kissinger and D.S. Roos.<br>
<b>Getting the most out of bioinformatics resources.</b> <br>
<i>In</i>: Malaria Parasites, A.P. Waters & C.J. Janse, editors.  Horizon, Norfolk UK. 2005. 

<p>
Khan, A., S. Taylor, C. Su, A.J. Mackey, J. Boyle, R. Cole, D. Glover, K. Tang, 
I.T. Paulsen, M. Berriman, J.C. Boothroyd, E.R. Pfefferkorn, J.P. Dubey, J.W. 
Ajioka, D.S. Roos, J.C. Wootton and L.D. Sibley.<br> 
<b>Composite genome map and recombination parameters derived from three archetypal 
lineages of <i>Toxoplasma gondii</i>.</b> <br>
Nucl. Acids Res. 2005 33:2980-2992.<br>
[ <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/33/9/2980">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/33/9/2980">Full text</a> | <a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/reprint/33/9/2
980">PDF</a> ]

<p>
Roos, D.S.<br>
<b>Themes and variations in apicomplexan parasite biology.</b><br>
Science. 2005 309:72-73.<br>
[ <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/summary/309/5731/72">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/full/309/5731/72">Full text</a> | <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/cgi/reprint/309/5731/72.pdf
">PDF</a> ]

<p>
Chaudhary, K., and D.S. Roos.<br>
Protozoan genomics for drug discovery.<br>
Nature Biotechnol. 2005 23:1089-1091.<br>
[ <a href="http://www.nature.com/nbt/journal/v23/n9/abs/nbt0905-1089.html">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://www.nature.com/nbt/journal/v23/n9/full/nbt0905-1089.html">Full text</a> | <a href="http://www.nature.com/nbt/journal/v23/n
9/pdf/nbt0905-1089.pdf">PDF</a> ]

<p>
Radke, J.R., M.S. Behnke, A.J. Mackey, J.B. Radke, D.S. Roos and M.W. White.<br>
<b>The transcriptome of <i>Toxoplasma gondii</i>.</b> <br> 
BMC Bioinformatics 2005:3-26.<br>
[ <a href="http://www.biomedcentral.com/1741-7007/3/26/abstract">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://www.biomedcentral.com/1741-7007/3/26">Full text</a> | <a href="http://www.biomedcentral.com/content/pdf/1741-7007-3-26.pdf">PDF</a> 
]

<p>
Stoeckert CJ Jr. <br>
<b>Functional genomics databases on the web.</b> <br>
Cell Microbiol. 2005 7(8), 1053-9<br>
[ <a href="http://www.blackwell-synergy.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1462-5822.2005.00553.x">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://www.blackwell-synergy.com/doi/full/10.1111/j.1462-5822.2005.00553.x">Full text</a> | <a href="http://www.blackw
ell-synergy.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/j.1462-5822.2005.00553.x">PDF</a> ]



<p>
Duraisingh M, Ferdig MT, Stoeckert CJ, Volkman SK, McGovern VP. <br>
<b><i>Plasmodium</i> research in the postgenomic era.</b>  <br>
Trends Parasitol. 2006 22(1):1-4 <br>
[ <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science?_ob=ArticleURL&amp;_udi=B6W7G-4HNSB6D-2&amp;_coverDate=01%2F31%2F2006&amp;_alid=373299208&amp;_rdoc=1&amp;_fmt=&amp;_orig=search&amp;_qd=1&amp;_cdi=6626&amp;_sort=d&amp;view=c&amp;
_acct=C000050221&amp;_version=1&amp;_urlVersion=0&amp;_userid=10&amp;md5=b4b05abd69cfeb5ef1e66ca91cce994b">Abstract</a> | <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science?_ob=ArticleURL&amp;_udi=B6W7G-4HNSB6D-2&amp;_user=10&amp;_co
verDate=01%2F31%2F2006&amp;_alid=373299208&amp;_rdoc=1&amp;_fmt=full&amp;_orig=search&amp;_qd=1&amp;_cdi=6626&amp;_sort=d&amp;_docanchor=&amp;view=c&amp;_acct=C000050221&amp;_version=1&amp;_urlVersion=0&amp;_userid=10&amp;md5=83
f0b10de2980b3fef183d3e7268b9b2">Full text</a> | <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science?_ob=MImg&amp;_imagekey=B6W7G-4HNSB6D-2-1&amp;_cdi=6626&amp;_user=10&amp;_orig=search&amp;_coverDate=01%2F31%2F2006&amp;_qd=1&amp;_sk=9
99779998&amp;view=c&amp;wchp=dGLzVlz-zSkzS&amp;md5=3b147441231bcdb654a864bd3256aab9&amp;ie=/sdarticle.pdf">PDF</a> ]



</div>


</td></tr>



</table>


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

</xmlAnswer>
