<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xmlAnswer>

<!--
   <record>
       <attribute name="headline"></attribute>
       <attribute name="date"></attribute>
       <attribute name="tag"></attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
--> 

<record>
       <attribute name="headline">EuPathDB Scientific Working Group</attribute>
       <attribute name="date">31 March 2010 15:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">swg_announce_2010</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
EuPathDB is pleased to announce the members of the scientific working group
(SWG). The SWG provides EuPathDB with scientific oversight and 
guidance.  Members of the SWG also review the driving biological projects initiative.<br><br>

<table>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://www.fnih.org/about">Michael Gottlieb</a>, Chair<br>
Foundation for National Institutes of Health (FNIH)<br>
Broad expertise in parasitology, large integrative projects (chair)<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.sanger.ac.uk/research/faculty/mberriman/">Matt Berriman</a><br>
Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute<br>
Pathogen genomics & functional annotation<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://med.stanford.edu/profiles/John_Boothroyd/">John Boothroyd</a><br>
Stanford University<br>
Toxoplasma biology & host-pathogen interactions<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.vcu.edu/micro/buck.htm">Greg Buck</a><br>
Virginia Commonwealth University<br>
Pathogenomics of apicomplexan and kinetoplastid parasites<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://www3.niaid.nih.gov/labs/aboutlabs/lmiv/default.htm">Patrick Duffy</a><br>
National Institutes of Health (NIAID)<br>
Laboratory & clinical aspects of malaria biology<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.cgm.northwestern.edu/">Pascale Gaudet</a><br>
Northwestern University<br>
Biocuration, ontologies, DIctyostelium<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://www.paras.uzh.ch/research/microbiology.html">Adrian Hehl</a><br>
University of  Zurich<br>
Cellular and molecular biology of Giardia<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.botany.ubc.ca/keeling/">Patrick Keeling</a><br>
University of British Columbia<br>
Comparative genomics<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://www.healthsystem.virginia.edu/internet/pathology/faculty/petri.cfm">Bill Petri</a><br>
University of Virginia<br>
Laboratory & clinical aspects of Entamoeba and diarrheal diseases<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.oicr.on.ca/Research/stein.htm">Lincoln Stein</a><br>
Ontario Cancer Center<br>
Bioinformatics tools & analysis<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://www.genome.gov/26525388">Lu Wang</a><br>
National Institutes of Health (NHGRI)<br>
Large-scale sequencing<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://tulip.liv.ac.uk/portal/pls/portal/tulwwwmerge.mergepage?p_template=rae_staff_vs&p_tulipproc=raestaff&p_params=%3Fp_func%3DSDVS%26p_select%3DRAE%26p_hash%3DA31689%26p_url%3D192%26p_template%3Drae_staff_vs">Jonathan Wastling</a><br>
University of Liverpool<br>
Proteomics of apicomplexan parasites<br>
</td>
</tr><tr>
<td>
<a href="http://www.einstein.yu.edu/home/faculty/profile.asp?id=4218">Louis Weiss</a><br>
Albert Einstein College of Medicine<br>
Microsporidia, Toxoplasma, and clinical microbiology<br>
</td>
<td>
<a href="http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/faculty/dyann-wirth/">Dyann Wirth</a><br>
Harvard School of Public Health<br>
Plasmodium population biology, drug discovery<br>
</td></table>
          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

<record>
       <attribute name="headline">GiardiaDB new features</attribute>
       <attribute name="date">15 March 2010 15:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">giardia_newFeatures_0310</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[

<span style="font-weight: bold;">We are pleased to 
announce new features in GiardiaDB 2.1<br><br> 
</span><span style="font-weight: bold;">New Features:</span><br><br>
<ul>
 <li>The gray tool bar at the top of all GiardiaDB web pages has 
been enhanced to include a link to the "My Basket" feature including an 
indication of how may items are in the basket.</li> 
 <li>The genome browser has been updated to version 1.7, which 
offers enhanced features and stability.&nbsp;</li> 
 <li>Weighted searches are now available. &nbsp;This feature 
allows you to assign an arbitrary weight to the searches (steps) in 
your search strategy making it possible for you to view a ranked list 
of your results.&nbsp;</li> 
</ul> 
<br>
<span style="font-weight: bold;">***<a href="https://mail.pcbi.upenn.edu/mailman/listinfo/eupathdb_testers">Sign up to be a EuPathDB feature evaluator:</a
>***<br><br>
</span> 
<div style="margin-left: 20px;">
We welcome you to <a href="https://mail.pcbi.upenn.edu/mailman/listinfo/eupathdb_testers">*sign up* to be an early evaluator</a>
 of new features on the EuPathDB sites.  This will be an opportunity for you to help us refine and improve features early in the development process.  
Signing up is easy.  Evaluating will require minimal effort on your part, 
typically in the form of answering specific questions, using the feature(s) and rendering your opinion.
</div>



          ]]>
       </attribute>
</record>

<record>
       <attribute name="headline">EuPathDB Driving Biological Projects</attribute>
       <attribute name="date">04 February 2010 15:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">eupath_dbp_2010</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
The NIAID-funded Eukaryotic Pathogen Genome Database
(<a href="http://eupathdb.org">EuPathDB.org</a>) invites proposals for Driving Biological
Projects (DBPs) focused on one or more of the eukaryotic
pathogens supported by this Bioinformatics Resource Center
(BRC). We anticipate making two awards of up to $600K each
by July 1, 2010 (a second round of solicitations is expected
in 2012).<i> A two page Letter of Intent (LOI) is due Feb 28,
following which full applications will be solicited by
invitation only, with a deadline of March 31.</i>  
<a href="http://eupathdb.org/common/EuPathDB_DBP_announcement.pdf">
Click here to
download the RFP</a>.

          ]]>
       </attribute>
</record>

<record>
       <attribute name="headline">"My Basket", A New Feature in GiardiaDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="date">22 December 2009 15:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">giardia1209news</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
We are pleased to announce the implementation&nbsp;a new tool in
GiardiaDB. &nbsp;The "My
Basket" tool allows you to select various genes from
your searches and add them to your basket (much like a shopping cart).
&nbsp;To add genes to your basket simply click on the basket icon
in a
result list or on a gene page. &nbsp;A green basket icon indicates
that a
genes is already in your basket. &nbsp;You can easily convert your
basket to
a strategy to save it and perform additional searches or combine it
with one of your already existing strategies.
&nbsp;Please note that using the basket feature requires you to
login first.

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
<record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
            <b>Working with Parasite Database Resources Workshop (April 17-21, 2010)</b>
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
         20 November 2009 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
         HinxtonWorkShop
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[<big><br>
We are pleased to announce a workshop taught as part of a collaboration between the Pathogen Genomics Group 
(Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute, UK), the Eukaryotic Pathogen Bioinformatics Resource Center 
(University of Georgia and University of Pennsylvania, US), and the Seattle Biomedical Research Institute (US). 
This residential workshop aims to provide experimental biologists with hands-on experience in 
genomic-scale data analysis, including genome browsers and comparison tools, methods for 
data integration, and resources for sophisticated data mining.
Many examples and exercises will be drawn from the kinetoplastida, including <i>Leishmania spp.</i>, 
<i>Trypanosoma brucei</i>, and <i>Trypanosoma cruzi</i>, although applicants working on other protozoan 
parasites will also benefit.<br><br>

<span style="font-weight: bold;"><span
 style="color: red;">!!!!!</span>Application Deadline
is December 18th 2009<span style="color: red;">!!!!!!</span></span>
<br><br>

<b>For registration and additional information (including scholarships) please click <a href="http://www.wellcome.ac.uk/Education-resources/Courses-and-conferences/Advanced-Courses/Courses/WTX057366.htm">here</a> (Note: you will be diverted to and external site).
</b><br><br>
As usual, if you have any questions please send us an <a href="mailto:help@eupathdb.org">Email</a>. 

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

<record>
       <attribute name="headline">GiardiaDB 2.0 released</attribute>
       <attribute name="date">16 November 2009 15:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">giardia1109news</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
<span style="font-weight: bold;">We are pleased to
announce the release of GiardiaDB 2.0<br>
<br>
</span>This is a major release of GiardiaDB that includes several
new data types:<br>
<br>
<ul>
  <li>Genome sequence and annotation of <span
 style="font-style: italic;">Giardia</span> <span
 style="font-style: italic;">intestinalis</span>
assemblage B isolate GS. &nbsp;For further information please refer
to the publication: <a
 href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19696920">Draft
genome sequencing of giardia intestinalis assemblage B isolate GS: is
human giardiasis caused by two different species? PLoS Pathog. 2009
Aug;5(8):e1000560 Franzén et al.</a></li>
</ul>
<ul>
  <li>Sequence and annotation of <span
 style="font-style: italic;">Giardia</span> assemblage
E isolate P15 was provided by J. Jerlstrom-Hultqvist. O. Franzen, E.
Castro, J. Ankarklev, D. Palm, J. O. Andersson, S.G. Svard and B.
Andersson (Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden and Uppsala
University, Uppsala, Sweden). The genome sequence and annotation was
graciously provided to GiardiaDB prepublication.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<div style="margin-left: 40px;"><span
 style="font-style: italic;">note: genomic data may be
searched in many ways such as identifying all genes from any of the
assemblages, searching for genes using the text search or identifying
genes from one assemblage based on functional data in another using
orthology. &nbsp;In addition, all gene pages include a genomic
context view </span><span style="font-style: italic;">highlighting
</span><span style="font-style: italic;">synteny
between the three assemblages in GiardiaDB.&nbsp; </span></div>
<ul>
  <li>Additional stress induction microarray data graciously
provided by Cornelia Spycher and Adrian Hehl prepublication (University
of Zürich, Switzerland). &nbsp;Genes may be identified based on
their expression profile by running one of the&nbsp;<a
 href="http://giardiadb.org/giardiadb/showQuestion.do?questionFullName=InternalQuestions.GenesByMicroarrayEvidence&amp;target=GENE">microarray
searches </a>and results may be combined with other searches in
GiardiaDB.</li>
</ul>
Additional features and Improvements:<br>
<br>
<ul>
  <li>1012 genes from Giardia lamblia assemblage A isolate WB
have been undeprecated based on synteny to assemblage B and E genomes.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
  <li>Representation of SAGE tag data on gene pages has been
improved providing graphical representation of tag counts over the life
cycle of the parasite.</li>
</ul>

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
<record>
       <attribute name="headline"><![CDATA[
         GiardiaDB 1.3 released
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">25 September 2009 15:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">giardia909news</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[<b>We are pleased to
announce the release of GiardiaDB 1.3</b><br>
<br>
<u>New Data:</u><br>
<ul>
  <li><il>G.
intestinalis</il> mitosome enriched fraction proteomics
provided by Jan Tachezy and described in <a
 href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19717741">Rada <il>et. al.</il></a></li>
  <li><il>Giardia</il>
isolate data from GenBank are now included -- search for isolates based
on many criteria such as geographic location, submitter name, isolation
source and/or host. &nbsp;Also, generate nucleotide sequence
alignments of isolates you select, and BLAST your sequence against the
isolate database. <br>
   </li>
</ul>
<u>New/Updated
Features:</u><br>
<ul>
  <li>Now after you perform a BlastN against genomic sequence you
can
link from the blast output to the correct coordinates in the genome
browser.&nbsp; This allows you to explore annotation and other
functional
data in relation to your BLAST hits.</li>
  <li>A table of paralogs (if any) is now available on gene pages
allowing you to view expanded gene families -- See <a
 href="http://giardiadb.org/giardiadb/showRecord.do?name=GeneRecordClasses.GeneRecordClass&amp;project_id=GiardiaDB&amp;primary_key=GL50803_15158">GL50803_15158&nbsp;</a>for
example (scroll down to the Orthologs and Paralogs Table).</li>
  <li>The type ahead feature has been implemented for GO term, EC
number and Interpro domain searches.</li>
  <li>You can now edit or delete your user comments.</li>
  <li>You can now modify your user profile, change your password
or your email address.</li>
</ul>
Please also note that the parent portal site <a
 href="http://eupathdb.org">EuPathDB</a> has just been
updated, offering you the ability to explore results across organisms.<br>
<br>
Sincerely,<br>
<br>
The EuPathDB team.
]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>
<record>
       <attribute name="headline"><![CDATA[
         GiardiaDB 1.2 released
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">14 July 2009 15:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">release12</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
We are pleased to announce the release of GiardiaDB 1.2
<p>
This release features a new user interface with added functionality and a graphical strategy system for building complex searches.
<p>
The new user interface contains many new features including:
<ul>
<li>  A new search strategy interface that enables users to more easily construct complex searches.
<li>  'User Comments' have been updated to enable submission of supporting evidence including pubmed identifiers and images (or other files). Comments may be added to any gene or sequence page, enhancing available annotation. 
<li>  Files can now be uploaded and provided to the community via the file repository section.
</ul>
<p>
The previous version of GiardiaDB may still be accessed <a href='http://old.giardiadb.org'>here</a>.
]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

 <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         EuPathDB to take on the kinetoplastida
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">
       1 December 2008 15:00
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">
       1December2008GatesFoundation
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[

We are pleased to report
an award from the <a href="http://www.gatesfoundation.org">Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation</a> in support of a
TrypDB component of the <a href="http://eupathdb.org/">EuPathDB</a> family of databases,
encompassing <i>Leishmania</i> species, <i>Trypanosoma brucei</i>, and
<i>Trypanosoma cruzi</i>.  A coordinated award from the<a href="http://www.wellcome.ac.uk/"> Wellcome Trust</a>
will permit enhanced annotation of kinetoplastid parasites. 
These projects represent a collaborative effort between the
GeneDB team (at the Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute), colleagues
at the <a href="http://www.sbri.org/">Seattle Biomedical Research Institute</a>, and the EuPathDB
team -- an NIAID-supported Bioinformatics Resource Center. Look
for the first release of TrypDB in Jan 2009!

 ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         GiardiaDB 1.1 Updated
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">18 November 2008 00:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">18Nov20081.1.2update</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
We are pleased to announce an update to GiardiaDB 1.1, which mainly affects the number of deprecated genes available through GiardiaDB and how query results are displayed.
<p>
1. In this release, all genes that were available through the genome project database (MBL GiardiaDB) are now included in GiardiaDB.  Hence, there are 4778 deprecated genes in this release.
<p>
2. When performing a query, you no longer select whether to query genes only, deprecated genes only, or both.  Instead, when a query is performed, all results will be returned with the option to view (or filter) all results, genes only or deprecated genes only (“genes only” is the default view of the results).
<p>
As a reminder, deprecated genes were labeled as such because they appear unlikely to represent true genes, based on incompatibility with longer gene models or alternative models for which functional evidence is available. A number of deprecated genes may in fact be true genes and as evidence becomes available to support this, we will elevate a deprecated gene to a "full" gene status.  We encourage users to notify us of such evidence by email or by adding specific user comments gene pages.
    ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

 <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         Free microarrays
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">18 November 2008 00:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">18Nov2008Microarrays</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[
Free microarrays:  Please note that the Pathogen Functional Genomics Resource Center (<a href=http://pfgrc.jcvi.org/index.php>PFGRC</a>) at the J. Craig Venter Institute (<a href=http://www.jcvi.org/>JCVI</a>) provides several resources for investigators including microarrays for <i>Giardia lamblia</i> (WB strain, clone C6).<br><br>

Click <a href=http://pfgrc.jcvi.org/index.php/microarray/available_microarrays.html>here</a> to view a list of available microarrays at PFGRC.

    ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>

 <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         GiardiaDB and TrichDB published in Nucleic Acids Research
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">1 October 2008 00:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">1Oct2008NAR</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[

We are pleased to announce the publication of the database paper
introducing both GiardiaDB and TrichDB in the database issue of Nucleic
Acid Research.
<p>
<a href="http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/full/gkn631">GiardiaDB and TrichDB: integrated genomic resources for the eukaryotic
protist pathogens Giardia lamblia and Trichomonas vaginalis.</a> Nucleic
Acids Research Advance Access published on September 29, 2008, DOI
10.1093/nar/gkn631.

          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         GiardiaDB 1.1 is released with new Microarray, Mass Spec., Assemblies and SAGE Data
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">12 May 2008 00:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">12May2008Release1.1</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[

We are pleased to announce that GiardiaDB is now available at <a href="/">www.giardiadb.org</a>.  GiardiaDB is now part of ApiDB/EuPathDB (<a href="http://eupathdb.org">www.eupathdb.org</a>) and funded by <a href="http://www.niaid.nih.gov/dmid/genomes/brc/default.htm">NIH's BRC program</a>.
<br><br>
  Please send a message to the support team from the link at the bottom of the GiardiaDB web page (<a href="/giardiadb/help.jsp"  target="_blank" onClick="poptastic(this.href); return false;">Contact Us!</a>).
<br><br>
GiardiaDB 1.1 provides the genome and annotation for the the eukaryotic parasite Giardia lamblia ATCC50803, WBC6 isolate, generated at the MBL and just reported in Science (Science 28 September 2007, Volume 317, pp. 1921-1926). 
<p>New data available in this release includes: 
<ul>
  <li>Genes which were subsumed or largely overlapping with longer genes or genes with more evidence were marked as deprecated and all gene queries allow users to choose whether to query for these genes or not.
  <li>Ten SAGE tag libraries are now available with queries and record pages.
  <li>Microarry data from experiments examining stress induction in trophozoites.
  <li>Proteomics data from trophozoites.
  <li>All locations are reported on scaffolds but also available in contig coordinates.
</ul>
GiardiaDB, like the other ApiDB/EuPathDB sites, offers researchers a plethora of  tools for genomic data mining.  In addition to BLAST and pattern/motif similarity searches, users can identify G. lamblia genes by genomic position; common name or keyword; gene attributes such as gene type and exon number; transcript expression evidence (ESTs and SAGE tags); physical characteristics of predicted proteins such as molecular weight and secondary structure;  predicted function from Gene Ontology and EC enzyme number annotation;  and cellular location.  In addition, GiardiaDB contains pre-computed phylogenetic trees for proteins with homologues in other eukaryotic genomes.
<br><br>
Regards,
<br>
The GiardiaDB team


          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


   <record>
       <attribute name="headline">
         <![CDATA[
         GiardiaDB 1.0 is released
         ]]>
       </attribute>
       <attribute name="date">1 October 2007 00:00</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">1October2007Release1.0</attribute>
       <attribute name="item">           
         <![CDATA[

We are pleased to announce that GiardiaDB is now available at <a href="/">www.giardiadb.org</a>.  GiardiaDB is now part of ApiDB (<a href="http://apidb.org">www.apidb.org</a>) and funded by <a href="http://www.niaid.nih.gov/dmid/genomes/brc/default.htm">NIH's BRC program</a>.
<br><br>
The previous GiardiaDB, hosted by the MBL's Bay Paul Center, will remain available until the end of 2007.  During this transition period, we ask that you use <a href="/">www.giardiadb.org</a> and notify us if there is a feature, tool, or query that you need that is not available at the new site.  Please send a message to the support team from the link at the bottom of the GiardiaDB web page (<a href="/giardiadb/help.jsp"  target="_blank" onClick="poptastic(this.href); return false;">Contact Us!</a>).
<br><br>
GiardiaDB 1.0 provides the genome and annotation for the the eukaryotic parasite Giardia lamblia ATCC50803, WBC6 isolate, generated at the MBL and just reported in Science (Science 28 September 2007, Volume 317, pp. 1921-1926).   Also provided are expression data from EST and SAGE surveys.
<br><br>
GiardiaDB, like the other ApiDB sites, offers researchers a plethora of  tools for genomic data mining.  In addition to BLAST and pattern/motif similarity searches, users can identify G. lamblia genes by genomic position; common name or keyword; gene attributes such as gene type and exon number; transcript expression evidence (ESTs and SAGE tags); physical characteristics of predicted proteins such as molecular weight and secondary structure;  predicted function from Gene Ontology and EC enzyme number annotation;  and cellular location.  In addition, GiardiaDB contains pre-computed phylogenetic trees for proteins with homologues in other eukaryotic genomes.
<br><br>
Regards,
<br>
The GiardiaDB team


          ]]>
       </attribute>
    </record>


</xmlAnswer>

