<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE xml [
  <!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"> 
  <!ENTITY lt   "&#60;"> 
  <!ENTITY gt   "&#62;">
  <!ENTITY sl   "&#47;">
]>

<xmlAnswer>

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">General Information</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">generalinfo</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
<![CDATA[
CryptoDB is an integrated genomic and functional genomic database for 
the parasite Cryptosporidium. CryptoDB integrates whole genome sequence and annotation along with experimental data and environmental isolate sequences provided by community researchers . The database includes supplemental bioinformatics analyses and a web interface for data-mining.
]]>

</attribute>
   </record>

  

   <record>
       <attribute name="title">Organisms included in CryptoDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">organisms</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
<ul>
<li><i>Cryptosporidium parvum</i></li>
<li><i>Cryptosporidium hominis</i></li>
<li><i>Cryptosporidium muris</i></li>
<li>environmental isolate sequences from numerous species</li>
</ul>
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Data Statistics</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">stats</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

<div id="cirbulletlist"><ul>
<li>The <a href = "/a/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.GenomeDataType">EuPathDB Data Summary</a> provides an overview of the content in Eu
PathDB across sites, all organisms and data types covered.
<li>The <a href="/a/showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.GeneMetrics">EuPathDB Gene Metrics Table</a> summarizes the number of genes for the o
rganisms currently available in EuPathDB, by various datatypes.
</ul></div>

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

<!--
 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Understanding Data: Protocols and Methods</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">protocols_methods</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

We are interested in including documents and protocols that are useful   
for the CryptoDB community.  Please send us your suggestions by   
clicking <a href="help.jsp" target="_blank" onClick="poptastic(this.href); return false;">here</a>.
<br><br>
<a href="/static/SOP/">SOPs for Annotation</a>


   ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>
-->
<record>
       <attribute name="title">Understanding Downloads</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">downloads</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
There are several kinds of downloads available in a EuPathDB site:
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
<li> Download files that we create at release time. The link to access these files is under the menu item "Downloads":"Data Files". These include fasta files for all available sequences, gff files with complete gene information, and other formats.
<li> Download files with results generated by running searches. From a result page (after running a search) a user can access the "Download Results" link, to a new page where a few different download formats are offered. The file for download includes all IDs in the result. The user selects a format and, in some formats, the user may request additional information about each ID in the result: single valued attributes (e.g., exon count for a geneID) and multi-valued tables (e.g., set of EC numbers for a geneID).
<li> Download files that have been uploaded by the community in our websites, available under "Downloads" or "Community".
<li> Download EuPathDB publications, under the menu item "Downloads".
</ul>
</div>
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Scientific Advisory Team</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">advisors</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

Each project in EuPathDB benefits from the advice and mentoring of people from each specific community.
<br><br>

<b>CryptoDB</b><br><br>
<div id="cirbulletlist">
<ul>
<li>Lihua Xiao (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, USA)
<li>Gregory Buck (Virginia Commonwealth University, USA)
<li>Giovanni Widmer (Tufts University, USA)
<li>Guan Zhu (Texas A&M University, USA)
</ul></div>
<br>
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


  <record>
       <attribute name="title">Acknowledgements</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">acks</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

EuPathDB wishes to acknowledge all the community members who
have contributed data (often pre-publication), entered user
comments or sent us their suggestions.
<br><br>
And the team behind EuPathDB:<br>
Cristina Aurrecoechea1, John Brestelli2,4, Brian P. Brunk2,7, Steve Fischer2,4, Bindu Gajria2,7, Xin Gao2,7, Alan Gingle3, Greg Grant2,4, Omar S. Harb2,7, Mark Heiges1, Frank Innamorato2,4, John Iodice2,4, Jessica C. Kissinger1,5, Eileen T. Kraemer6, Wei Li2,7, John A. Miller6, Vishal Nayak2,4, Cary Pennington1, Deborah F. Pinney2,4, David S. Roos7, Chris Ross1, Ganesh Srinivasamoorthy1, Christian J. Stoeckert Jr. 2,4, Ryan Thibodeau1, Charles Treatman2,7, Haiming Wang1
<br><br>
<ul>
<li>1Center for Tropical & Emerging Global Diseases, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602 USA
<li>2Penn Center for Bioinformatics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA 19104 USA
<li>3Center for Applied Genetic Technologies, University of Georgia, Athens, GA, 30602 USA
<li>4Department of Genetics, University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine, Philadelphia, PA 19104 USA
<li>5Department of Genetics, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602 USA
<li>6Department of Computer Science, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602 USA
<li>7Department of Biology, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA 19104 USA
</ul>

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>



 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">funding</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
CryptoDB is a member of pathogen-databases that are housed under 
the NIAID-funded <a href="http://www.eupathdb.org">EuPathDB</a> 
Bioinformatics Resource Center (BRC) umbrella. The EuPathDB team is 
mainly distributed between the University of Pennsylvania in 
Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and the University of Georgia in Athens, 
Georgia.
       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>



 <record>
       <attribute name="title">Data Access Policy</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">use</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
The data at this site is provided freely for public use, through
the contributions of many researchers including those involved in
generating the genome sequences. The data is not guaranteed to be
accurate as it often reflects the results of ongoing research.
When using data obtained from any EuPathDB project, it is important to cite
the original publications and contributors of that data. 

Please see Citing CryptoDB below.

       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>


<record>
       <attribute name="title">Citing CryptoDB</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">citing</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
When citing CryptoDB itself, please use:
<br><br>
<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/sites/entrez?db=pubmed&cmd=search&term=16381902">
CryptoDB: a Cryptosporidium bioinformatics resource update.</a> 2006 Jan 1;34:D419-22. Heiges M, et al.

<br><br>Much of the data in CryptoDB is provided by independent researchers.  Please cite them if you use their data.  For a list of the data integrated into CryptoDB and the related publications please see <a href="showXmlDataContent.do?name=XmlQuestions.DataSources" class="blue"> Data Sources</a>.


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

<!--    
<record>
       <attribute name="title">Documents and Publications</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag">docs_pubs</attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[
We are interested in including documents and protocols that are useful   
for the CryptoDB community.  Please send us your suggestions by   
clicking <a href="help.jsp" target="_blank" onClick="poptastic(this.href); return false;">here</a>.


       ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>
-->


<record>
       <attribute name="title">Additional Information</attribute>
       <attribute name="tag"></attribute>
       <attribute name="text">
       <![CDATA[

<a href="/static/SOP/">SOPs for Annotation</a>


   ]]>
       </attribute>
   </record>

</xmlAnswer>
